{\move(10,10,190,230,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000&\3c&H00FFFF&}anoXmous
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous
Captain, I'd like to request that
It be me who's the attorney....
That it be myself who's assigned....
No, I'd like to request
That it be I who am assigned....
“That it be I who am assigned”?
That's confidence-inspiring.
Good grammar, there.
Captain, I'd like to request....
Lieutenant Commander Galloway,
Here to see Captain West.
-Go right in, they're expecting you.
-Thank you.
-Jo, come on in.
-Thank you, sir.
Captain West,
This is Lt. Commander Galloway.
-You know Commander Lawrence?
-Yes, sir.
-I appreciate you seeing me.
-Would you like to sit down?
-I'm fine, sir.
-Have a seat.
-We've had some trouble in Cuba?
-Yes, sir. This past Friday.
Two Marines, a Lance Corporal Dawson
And a Private Downey...
...entered the barracks room of a PFC
William Santiago and assaulted him.
Santiago died at the base hospital
Approximately an hour later.
The NIS agent who took Dawson
and Downey's statements...
...maintains they were trying
to stop Santiago...
...from naming Dawson
in a fenceline shooting incident.
-The hearing's in Cuba at 16:00.
-What's the problem?
Dawson and Downey are
recruiting-poster Marines.
Santiago was known to be a screw-up.
I was thinking it sounded
like a Code Red.
Christ!
Sir, I'd like to have them moved up
to Washington and assigned counsel.
Someone who can really look into this.
Someone who possesses
not only the legal skill...
...but a familiarity with
the workings of the military.
In short, I'd like to suggest that
I be the one who that--
That it be me who is assigned
to represent them, myself.
-Why don't you get a cup of coffee?
-Thank you, sir, I'm fine.
Leave the room, so we can
talk about you behind your back.
Certainly, sir.
I thought this Code Red shit wasn't
going on anymore.
With the Marines at Gitmo, who
knows what the hell goes on there?
We'd better find out before
the rest of the world does.
What about this
Commander Galloway?
She's been working a desk at
Internal Affairs for a little over a year.
-Before that?
-Disposed of three cases in two years.
Three in two years?
Who's she handling, the Rosenberg’s?
-She's not a litigator.
-She's a hell of an investigator--
In Internal Affairs, sure. She can
crawl up a lawyer's ass with the best.
I know, I know, all passion,
no street smarts. Bring her back in.
Jo.
-We'll have the defendants moved here.
-Thank you, sir.
And I'll have Division
assign them counsel.
But, not me?
From what I understand,
you're much too valuable...
...to be wasted on a five-minute
plea bargain and a week's paperwork.
-Sir, there might be more involved.
-Don't worry about it.
Division will assign the right man
for the job.
All right, let's go, let's get two!
Sorry.
Nothing to be sorry about, Sherby.
Look the ball into your glove.
-Shooting two.
-Sorry.
Trust me. Keep your eyes open, your
chances of catching increase by 10.
-Kaffee.
-Let's try it again.
-Kaffee!
-Dave, you seem distraught.
We were supposed to meet
15 minutes ago.
You're stalling on the McDermott case.
We either get it done now,
or I'll hang him from a fucking yardarm!
Do we still hang people?
from yardarms?
I don't think so.
Sherby doesn't think
we do that anymore.
I'll charge him with possession
and being under the influence on duty.
You plead guilty,
I'll recommend 30 days in the brig.
-It was 10 dollars' worth of oregano.
-Your client thought it was marijuana.
My client's a moron. That's not illegal.
I got people to answer to.
I'm gonna charge him.
With possession of a condiment?
I tried to help, but if you ask for
jail time, I'll file a motion to dismiss.
-You won't get it.
-I will get it.
If not, I'll file a motion seeking to obtain
an evidentiary ruling in advance...
...then I'll file against
pre-trial confinement.
You'll get three months' paperwork...
...because a signalman bought
and smoked a dime bag of oregano.
Let's go! Let's get two!
-Twenty days in the brig.
-Fifteen days' restricted duty.
-I don't know why I'm agreeing.
-You have wisdom beyond your years.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, captain.
How's the baby, Sam?
-She'll say her first word any day now.
-How can you tell?
She just looks like
she has something to say.
Excuse me, sorry I'm late.
You don't have a good excuse,
so I won't force you to tell a bad one.
-Thank you, sir.
-This first one's for you.
You're moving up in the world.
You've been requested by Division.
-Requested to do what?
-Guantánamo Bay, Cuba.
A Marine Corporal named Dawson
illegally fires a round...
...from his weapon,
over the fenceline and into Cuba.
-What's a fenceline?
-Sam.
A big wall separating
the good guys from the bad guys.
Teacher's pet.
PFC Santiago threatens
to rat on Dawson...
...to the Naval Investigative Service.
Dawson and another member
of his squad, PFC Louden Downey...
...go into Santiago's room,
tie him up...
...stuff a rag down his throat...
...and an hour later, he's dead.
Attending physician says the rag
was treated with some kind of toxin.
-They poisoned the rag?
-Not according to them.
-What do they say?
-Not much.
They're being flown up tomorrow.
On Wednesday at 06:00...
...you'll catch a transport down
to Cuba to find out what you can.
Meantime, go and see
Lt. Commander Joanne Galloway...
...with Internal Affairs.
-Any questions?
-The flight to Cuba...
...was that 06:00 in the morning, sir?
It's important this one go by the book,
so I'm assigning co-counsel.
Any volunteers?
-No.
-Sam....
-Sir, I got a stack of papers--
-Work with Kaffee on this.
Doing what?
He'll have this done in four days.
Doing various administrative things.
Backup. Whatever.
In other words,
I have no responsibilities?
Right.
My kind of case.
Right. Right. Okay, but I gotta have
that report by Wednesday.
-Hi.
-Hold on. Hi.
Daniel Kaffee. I was told to meet with...
...Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
-About a briefing.
-I'll call you back.
You're the attorney
Division assigned?
I'm lead counsel,
this is Sam Weinberg.
-I have no responsibilities whatsoever.
-Come in. Have a seat.
-How long have you been in the Navy?
-Going on nine months now.
And how long have you been
out of law school?
Little over a year.
-I see.
-Have I done something wrong?
No. But when I asked for counsel,
I was hoping to be taken seriously.
No offense taken,
in case you were wondering.
Lieutenant Kaffee is considered
the best litigator in our office.
He successfully plea-bargained
44 cases in nine months.
-One more, I get a set of steak knives.
-Have you ever been in court?
-I once had my license suspended....
-Danny.
If this thing goes to court, they won't
need a lawyer, they'll need a priest.
No, they'll need a lawyer.
Dawson's family's been contacted.
Downey's closest relative is his aunt.
She hasn't been contacted yet,
would you like me to do that?
Sure, if you feel like it.
One of the people you'll be seeing
is the barracks CO, Colonel Jessep.
I assume you've heard of him.
Who hasn't?
He's been in the papers lately.
He's expected to be
director of operations...
...of the National Security Council.
-Really?
-Here are Santiago's letters from Gitmo.
-That's Guantánamo Bay.
-I knew that one.
He wrote the fleet commander,
HQ Atlantic...
...the Marine commandant,
even his senator.
He wanted to be transferred.
No one was listening. Are you with me?
Yeah.
Finally he wrote the
Naval Investigative Service...
...where he offered to trade information
about Dawson's shooting for a transfer.
Right. Is that all?
This letter makes it look like your client
had a motive to kill Santiago.
-Got you. And Santiago is who?
-The victim.
Write that down.
These letters don't paint a flattering
picture of Marine Corps life at Gitmo?
-Yes, amon--
-And am I right...
...that a protracted investigation might
embarrass the Security Council guy?
-Colonel Jessep--
-Twelve years.
I'm sorry?
I'll get them to drop “conspiracy” and
“conduct unbecoming.” Twelve years.
You haven't talked to a witness
or looked at a piece of paper.
Pretty impressive, huh?
You'll have to go deeper than that.
Do you have some jurisdiction here
I should know about?
My job is to make sure
that you do your job.
I'm special counsel for Internal Affairs.
So my jurisdiction's in your face.
Read the letters. I'll expect
a report when you return from Cuba.
-Sure.
-You're dismissed!
I always forget that part.
He's a little preoccupied.
Team's playing Bethesda Medical
next week.
Tell your friend not to get cute.
Guantánamo Marines are fanatical.
-About what?
-About being Marines.
Dear sir, my name is
PFC William T. Santiago.
I'm a Marine stationed
at Marine barracks...
...Rifle Security Company Windward,
2nd Platoon Bravo.
l am writing to inform you
of my problems here in Cuba...
...and to ask for your help.
I've fallen out of runs before,
because of dizziness or nausea.
But on May 18th, I'd fallen back about
20 yards...
...going down a rocky, unstable hill.
My sergeant grabbed me
and pushed me down the hill...
...then I saw all black and the last thing
I remember is hitting the deck.
I was brought to the hospital.
They said it was heat exhaustion.
I ask you to help me.
Please, l need a transfer out of RSC.
Sincerely, PFC William T. Santiago,
U.S. Marine Corps.
P.S. In exchange for my transfer,
I'm willing to provide you....
“--with information about an illegal
fenceline shooting on August 2nd.”
Who the fuck is
PFC William T. Santiago?
Private Santiago's a member
of 2nd Platoon Bravo, sir.
Yeah. Apparently he's not very happy
down here at Shangri-la...
...because he's written everybody
but Santa Claus, asking for a transfer.
Now he's telling tales about
a fenceline shooting. Matthew?
-I'm appalled, sir.
-You're appalled.
This kid broke the chain of command
and ratted on a member of his unit...
...to say nothing of the fact
that he's a U.S. Marine...
...and it would appear he can't run
from here to there without collapsing.
What the fuck is going on
in Bravo company, Matthew?
Colonel, I think it would be better
to discuss it in private.
That won't be necessary.
I can handle this situation, sir.
-Like you handled Curtis Bell?
-Sir, your methods--
Don't interrupt me, lieutenant,
I'm your superior!
And I'm yours, Matthew.
I wanna know what
we're going to do about this.
I think Santiago should be
transferred immediately.
He's that bad?
And word of this letter will get out,
and he'll get his ass whipped.
Transfer Santiago? Yes.
Sure, you're right.
I'm sure that's the thing to do.
Wait. Wait, I've got a better idea.
Let's transfer the whole squad
off the base. Let's....
On second thought, Windward.
Let's transfer the whole
Windward division off the base.
Jon, go get those boys off the fence.
They're packing their bags.
-Tom!
-Sir?
Get me the president on the phone.
We're surrendering our position
in Cuba.
-Yes, sir.
-Wait a minute, Tom.
Don't get the president yet. Maybe we
should consider this for a second.
-Dismissed, Tom.
-Yes, sir.
Maybe-- And I'm just spit-balling here.
Maybe we have a responsibility
as officers to train Santiago.
Maybe we, as officers,
have a responsibility to this country...
...to see that the men and women
charged with its security...
...are trained professionals.
Yes, I'm certain that I read that
somewhere once.
And now I'm thinking,
Colonel Markinson...
...that your suggestion
of transferring Santiago...
...while expeditious
and certainly painless...
...might not be, in a manner
of speaking, the American way.
Santiago stays where he is.
We're gonna train the lad.
Jon, you're in charge.
Santiago doesn't make 4.6, 4.6
on his next proficiency report...
...I'm going to blame you.
-Then I'm going to kill you.
-Yes, sir.
I think that's a mistake, colonel.
Matthew, I think I will have
that word in private with you now.
Jon, that's all. Why don't we meet
at the “O” Club and have lunch...
...and we'll talk about the training
of young William.
I'd be delighted to hear
your suggestions.
Dismissed.
Matthew, sit down. Please.
-What do you think of Kendrick?
-I don't think my opinion of Kendrick--
I think he's pretty much
of a weasel myself.
But he's an awfully good officer...
...and in the end, we see eye to eye
on the best way to run a Marine unit.
We're in the business
of saving lives, Matthew.
That is a responsibility
that we have to take pretty seriously.
And I believe that taking a Marine
who is not up to the job...
...and shipping him off to another
assignment puts lives in danger.
Sit down, Matthew.
We go back a while.
We went to the Academy together...
...were commissioned together,
did our tours in Vietnam together.
But I've been promoted with
greater speed and success than you.
Now, if that's a source of tension
or embarrassment for you...
...I don't give a shit.
We're in the business of saving lives,
Lieutenant Colonel Markinson.
Don't ever question my orders
in front of another officer.
All the paperwork's in order.
Step over there.
-Hal, is this Washington D.C.?
-All right, let's move.
Yes, sir.
Got all of that one.
Excuse me. I wanted to talk to you
about Dawson and Downey.
-Say again?
-Dawson and Downey.
The names seem familiar, but....
Dawson. Downey. Your clients?
The Cuba thing! Yes!
Oh, Dawson and Downey. Right.
I've done something wrong again,
haven't I?
I was wondering why they're locked up
while their lawyer's out hitting a ball.
-We need the practice.
-That wasn't funny.
It was a little funny.
Lieutenant, would you be very insulted
if I recommended different counsel?
-Why?
-I don't think you're fit to handle it.
You don't even know me. Ordinarily
it takes someone hours to find that out.
Oh, come on. That was damn funny.
You're wrong. I do know you.
Daniel Alistair Kaffee,
born June 8th, 1964...
...at Boston Mercy Hospital.
Your father's Lionel Kaffee,
former Attorney General of the U.S...
...died 1985.
You went to Harvard Law,
then joined the Navy...
...probably because that's
what your father wanted.
Now you're just treading water
for the three years in the JAG corps...
...just laying low till you can
get out and get a real job.
If that's the situation,
that's fine, I won't tell anyone.
But if this case is handled in the same
fast-food, slick-assed manner...
...with which you handle
everything else...
...then something's
gonna get missed.
And I wouldn't be doing my job if I let
Dawson and Downey to sit in prison...
...because their attorney predetermined
the path of least resistance.
I'm sexually aroused, commander.
I don't think your clients
murdered anyone.
-What are you basing this on?
-There was no intent.
Doctor's report says Santiago died
of asphyxiation...
...from acute lactic acidosis...
...and the nature of the acidosis
strongly suggests poisoning.
Now, I don't know what that means,
but it sounds bad.
Santiago died at 1 a.m.
At 3, the doctor didn't know the reason.
Two hours later, he said it was poison.
Oh, now I see what you're saying.
It had to be Professor Plum,
in the library, with the candlestick.
I'm gonna talk to your supervisor.
Go straight up Pennsylvania Avenue.
It's the big white house with the pillars.
-Thank you.
-I don't think you'll have much luck.
I was assigned by Division.
Somebody thinks I'm a good lawyer.
So, while I appreciate your interest and
enthusiasm, I think I can handle things.
You know what a Code Red is?
What a pity.
-Morning, sir.
-Morning.
Officer on deck, ten-hut!
Lance Corporal Harold Dawson, sir!
Rifle Security Company Windward!
Second Platoon Bravo!
You haven't been working
and playing well with others.
Sir! Yes, sir!
Sir! PFC Louden Downey, sir!
I'm Daniel Kaffee,
this is Sam Weinberg. Sit down.
-Is this your signature?
-Yes, sir.
Don't have to call me sir.
Is this yours?
-Sir, yes, sir!
-Certainly don't need to say it twice.
-What's a Code Red?
-It's a disciplinary engagement.
What's that mean exactly?
A Marine falls out of line,
it's up to his unit to get him on track.
-What's a garden-variety Code Red?
-Sir?
Harold, You say “sir” and I look for
my father. Danny, Daniel Kaffee.
Garden-variety. Typical.
What's a basic Code Red?
A Marine refuses to bathe,
the men give him a GI shower.
-What's that?
-Scrub brushes, steel wool.
Beautiful.
Was the attack on Santiago
a Code Red?
Yes, sir.
Does he ever talk?
Sir, PFC Downey will answer
any direct questions you ask him.
Private Downey, the rag you put
in his mouth, was there poison on it?
-No, sir.
-Silver polish, turpentine, antifreeze?
No, sir. We were just
gonna shave his head.
When, all of the sudden....
We saw blood
dripping down his mouth.
We pulled the tape off and there was
blood all down his face, sir.
That's when Lance Corporal Dawson
called the ambulance.
-Did anyone see you call it?
-No, sir.
-Were you there when it arrived?
-Yes, that's when we were arrested.
On August 2nd, did you fire a shot
across the fenceline, into Cuba?
-Yes, sir.
-Why?
-My mirror engaged, sir.
-His “mirror”?
For every American sentry, there's
a Cuban counterpart. Called “mirrors.”
Lance corporal claims his mirror
was about to fire at him.
Santiago's letter to the NIS
said you fired illegally.
He's saying the guy, the mirror,
he never made a move.
Oh, Harold?
You see what I'm getting at?
If Santiago didn't have
anything on you...
...why did you give him
a Code Red?
-He broke the chain of command, sir.
-He what?
He went outside of his unit.
If he had a problem, he should have
spoken to me, then his sergeant, then--
All right, all right. Did you
assault Santiago with intent to kill?
-No, sir.
-What was your intent?
-To train him, sir.
-Train him to do what?
To think of his unit before himself.
To respect the code.
-What's the code?
-Unit, Corps, God, country!
-I beg your pardon?
-Unit, Corps, God, country, sir.
The government of the United States
wants to charge you two with murder.
And you want me to tell the prosecutor,
“unit, Corps, God, country”?
That's our code, sir.
-That's your code.
We'll be back.
You need anything? Books? Papers?
Cigarettes? Ham sandwich?
Sir! No, thank you, sir!
Harold, there's a concept
you'd better start warming up to.
-Sir?
-I'm the only friend you've got.
-Dan Kaffee.
-Smiling Jack Ross.
-Welcome to the big time.
-You think so?
Let's hope you practice law
better than you play softball.
Unfortunately, I don't do anything
better than I play softball.
I'm out of here, Jannelle!
See you when I get back from Cuba.
-Say hi to Castro for me.
-Will do. What're we looking at?
They plead guilty, we drop “conspiracy”
and “conduct unbecoming”...
...20 years, they're home in half.
-Twelve. They called the ambulance.
-I don't care. They killed a Marine.
The rag was tested for poison.
The autopsy says maybe, maybe not.
The Chief of Internal Medicine
at Guantánamo says he's sure.
-What do you know about Code Reds?
-Oh, man....
-Are we off the record?
-You tell me.
I'm gonna give you the 12 years.
But before you get into trouble
tomorrow, you should know...
...the platoon commander, Kendrick,
held a meeting with the men...
...and specifically told them
not to touch Santiago.
-We still playing hoops tomorrow?
-Do we have a deal?
I'll talk to you when I get back.
Hi there.
Any luck getting me replaced?
Is there anyone in this command
you don't drink or play softball with?
Listen, I came to make peace.
We got off on the wrong foot.
-What do you say, friends?
-Look, I don't--
I brought Downey some comic books
he was asking for.
The kid, I swear, doesn't even know
why he's been arrested.
-Commander--
-You can call me JoAnne. Or Jo.
-Jo?
-Yes.
Jo, if you speak to a client of mine
again without permission...
...I'll have you disbarred. Friends?
-I had authorization.
-From where?
Downey's closest relative, Ginny Miller,
his aunt on his mother's side.
You got authorization from Aunt Ginny?
I gave her a call, like you asked.
Very nice woman.
We spoke for an hour.
You got authorization from Aunt Ginny.
Perfectly within my province.
Does Aunt Ginny have a barn?
We could hold the trial there.
I can sew the costumes,
Uncle Goober can be the judge.
I'm going to Cuba with you tomorrow.
And the hits just keep on coming.
-How's it going, Luther?
-Another day, another dollar.
-Gotta play them as they lay.
-What goes around comes around.
-Can't beat them, join them.
-At least I got my health.
Well, you got everything.
See you tomorrow, Luther.
Not if I see you first.
You're my witness. The baby spoke.
My daughter said a word.
She made a sound.
I'm not sure it was a word.
-Come on! It was definitely a word.
-Okay.
You heard her.
She pointed and said “Pa.” She did.
-She was pointing at a mailbox.
-That's right.
Pointing as if to say,
“Pa! Look, a mailbox.”
-Jack Ross offered me the 12 years.
-That's what you wanted, right?
I know, and I'll....
-I mean, I guess I'll take it.
-So..?
It took about 45 seconds.
He barely put up a fight.
Danny, take the 12 years, it's a gift.
You don't believe their story, do you?
You think they ought to go
to jail for life.
I believe every word of their story...
...and I think they ought to
go to jail for life.
-See you tomorrow.
-Okay.
Don't forget to wear the whites.
Very hot.
I don't like the whites.
Nobody does, but we're going to Cuba.
You got Dramamine?
-Dramamine keeps you cool?
-No, it keeps you from getting airsick.
I get airsick because I'm afraid
of crashing. Dramamine won't help.
I got some oregano,
I hear that works pretty good.
Ross said the strangest thing to me
right before I left.
He said Lieutenant Kendrick...
...had told the men specifically
not to touch Santiago.
-So?
-I don't even know who Kendrick is.
What the hell. I'll see you tomorrow.
I'm Corporal Barnes, I'm to escort you
to the Windward side of the base.
I got some camouflage jackets,
I suggest you both put them on.
Camouflage jackets?
Yes, sir. We'll be riding
pretty close to the fenceline.
If the Cubans see an officer in white,
they might take a shot.
Good call, Sam.
We'll just hop on the ferry.
We'll be there in no time.
-Hold it. We gotta take a boat?
-Yes, sir, to get across the bay.
-No one said anything about a boat.
-Is there a problem, sir?
No, no problem,
I'm just not that crazy about boats.
Jesus Christ, Kaffee,
you're in the Navy, for crying out loud!
-Nobody likes her very much.
-Yes, sir.
-Nathan Jessep. Come on in.
-Thank you, sir.
Daniel Kaffee, I'm the attorney
for Dawson and Downey.
This is Lt. Commander
JoAnne Galloway.
Pleasure meeting you.
Observing and evaluating.
Lieutenant Weinberg, my assistant.
This is XO, Colonel Markinson,
and Platoon Leader Lt. Kendrick.
I've asked them to join us.
Sit down, please.
-Lieutenant Kaffee.
-Colonel Markinson.
I had the pleasure of meeting
your father once.
I was a teenager.
He spoke at my high school.
-Lionel Kaffee?
-Yes, sir.
Well, what do you know?
Jon, this man's dad once made a lot
of enemies in your neck of the woods.
Jefferson v.
Madison County School District.
Folks down there said a little black girl
couldn't go to an all-white school.
Lionel Kaffee said,
“We'll just see about that.”
-How the hell is your dad, Danny?
-He passed away seven years ago.
-Don't I feel like the fucking asshole.
-Not at all, sir.
-What can we do for you, Danny?
-Not much, sir.
This is really a formality
more than anything else.
JAG Corps insist we interview
all the relevant witnesses.
The JAG Corps can be
demanding that way.
Jon'll show you what you want to see.
After that, we can meet for lunch.
-How does that sound?
-Fine, sir.
You met with the men that afternoon.
What did you guys talk about?
I told them we had
an informer among us...
...and that, despite any desire
they had for retribution...
...Private Santiago was not
to be harmed in any way.
-What time was that meeting?
-1600.
That's 4:00.
We should make sure somebody
gets this to his parents.
-We don't need it anymore.
-Right.
-Lt. Kendrick, may I call you Jon?
-No, you may not.
-Have I done something to offend you?
-No, I like all you Navy boys.
Every time we gotta go fight,
you fellas always give us a ride.
Lieutenant Kendrick,
do you think Santiago was murdered?
I believe in God and Jesus Christ.
Because I do, I can say this:
Private Santiago is dead,
and that is a tragedy.
But he is dead because he had
no code...
...and no honor.
And God was watching.
-How do you feel about that theory?
-Sounds good. Let's move on.
Are you planning on investigating,
or you just gonna take the guided tour?
I'm pacing myself.
They were running around for hours
looking for anything white to wave.
Some of these people surrendered
to a crew from CNN.
Walk softly and carry an armoured
tank division, I always say.
-That was delicious. Thank you.
-My pleasure, sir.
Colonel, I do have to ask you a
couple questions about September 6th.
Shoot.
An NIS agent told you that Santiago
tipped him off to a fenceline shooting.
Santiago was gonna reveal who did it
in exchange for a transfer.
Yes.
If you feel there are any details
that I'm missing, feel free to speak up.
Thank you.
You called Lt. Colonel Markinson...
...and Lt. Kendrick into your office.
Is that right?
-Yes.
-And what happened then?
We agreed that, for his own safety,
Santiago should be transferred.
Santiago was set to be transferred?
On the first flight to the States.
06:00 the next morning.
Five hours too late, as it turned out.
Yeah. All right, that's all.
Thanks very much for your time.
The corporal's waiting outside
with a jeep. He'll take you back.
-Wait, I've got some questions.
-No, you don't.
-Yes, I do.
On the morning Santiago died,
did you meet with Dr. Stone?
-Of course. One of my men was dead.
-You see? The man was dead. Let's go.
-Have you heard the term Code Red?
-I've heard the term, yes.
This past February,
you received a memo...
...from the Atlantic Fleet commander...
...warning that enlisted men
disciplining their own...
...wasn't to be condoned.
I submit to you that
whoever wrote that memo...
...has never faced the working end
of a Cuban AK-47 assault rifle.
However, the directive,
having come from the commander...
...I gave it its due attention.
What is your point, Jo?
She has no point, it's part of her charm.
We're out of here. Thank you.
My point is that I think
Code Reds still go on. Do they?
-He doesn't need to answer that.
-Yes, he does.
-No, he really doesn't.
-Yeah, he really does.
Colonel?
You know, it just hit me.
-She outranks you, Danny.
-Yes, sir.
I want to tell you something.
And listen up, because I mean this.
You're the luckiest man in the world.
There is nothing on this earth sexier--
Believe me, gentlemen.
--than a woman you have to salute
in the morning.
Promote them all, I say,
because this is true.
If you haven't gotten a blowjob
from a superior officer, well...
...you're just letting the best in life
pass you by.
The practice of Code Reds is still
condoned on this base, isn't it?
My problem is I'm a colonel,
so I'll just have to take cold showers...
...until they elect some gal president.
I need an answer to my question, sir.
Take caution in your tone, commander.
I'm a fair guy, but this fucking heat
is making me absolutely crazy.
You wanna ask me about Code Reds?
On the record,
I discourage the practice...
...in accordance with the directive.
Off the record, I tell you it is
an invaluable part of infantry training.
If it goes on without my knowledge,
so be it. That's how I run my unit.
You want to investigate me,
roll the dice and take your chances.
I eat breakfast 300 yards from 4000
Cubans who are trained to kill me.
So don't think for one second that you
can come down here, flash a badge...
...and make me nervous.
Let's go.
Colonel, I'll just need a copy
of Santiago's transfer order.
What's that?
Santiago's transfer order.
You guys have paperwork on it.
I just need it for the file.
-For the file?
-Yeah.
Of course you can have a copy
of the transfer order for the file.
-I'm here to help in any way I can.
-Thank you.
You believe that, don't you, Danny?
That I'm here to help you
any way I can?
Of course.
The corporal will take you by Personnel
on your way to the flight line...
...and you can have all
the transfer orders that you want.
But you have to ask me nicely.
-I beg your pardon?
-You have to ask me nicely.
See, I can deal with the bullets,
the bombs and the blood.
I don't want money
and I don't want medals.
What I do want
is for you to stand there...
...in that faggoty white uniform...
...and with your Harvard mouth,
extend me some fucking courtesy.
You got to ask me nicely.
Colonel Jessep,
if it's not too much trouble...
...I'd like a copy of the transfer order.
Sir.
No problem.
-Who is it?
-It's me.
Jo.
I've really missed you.
I was just saying,
it's been three hours--
-Markinson's disappeared.
-What?
Colonel Markinson's gone U.A.
Unauthorized Absence.
-I know what it means. When?
-This afternoon, after we left.
-I'll try to find him in the morning.
-I've already tried.
You tried?
You're coming close to interfering
with a government investigation.
I'm Louden Downey's attorney.
Aunt Ginny feels like she knows me.
So I suggested that I get more
directly involved with the case.
She had Louden sign the papers
about an hour ago.
I suppose it's too much to hope that
you're making this up just to bother me.
-Don't worry, you're still lead counsel.
-Splendid.
I think Kendrick ordered the Code Red,
and so do you.
Let's go.
Officer on deck, ten-hut!
-Did Kendrick order the Code Red?
-Sir?
Don't say “sir” like I just asked you
if you cleaned the latrine.
Did Lieutenant Kendrick order you
to give Santiago a Code Red?
Yes, sir.
-Did he?
-Yes, sir.
-Why didn't you mention this before?
-You didn't ask us, sir.
Corporal, I get paid no matter
how much time you spend in jail.
Yes, sir. I know you do, sir.
-Fuck you, Harold!
-All right.
-At ease. Let's sort this thing out.
-Shit.
There was a platoon meeting
on September 6th at 4 p.m.
Lieutenant Kendrick says he told you
nothing was to happen to Santiago.
Now, is this true?
I want you to speak freely.
Ma'am, that's correct.
But then he dismissed the platoon.
-And what happened then?
-Lt. Kendrick came to our room.
When?
About five minutes after the
meeting broke. About 16:20.
And what happened then?
Lt. Kendrick ordered us
to give Santiago a Code Red.
Jack! Jack!
They were given an order.
-Jack, come on.
-I'll be right back. Be right back.
How long did you know
about the order?
I didn't. Who's this?
It's Jo Galloway, Downey's lawyer.
She's very pleased to meet you.
-What are you accusing me of?
-How long have you known?
He didn't know. If he did and didn't tell
us, he'd be violating the code of ethics.
He's got enough to worry about.
God forbid our clients plead not guilty...
...and testify for the record
they were ordered.
Kendrick told those men
not to touch Santiago.
Then he told Dawson and Downey to
give him a Code Red. Kendrick's lying.
-You have proof?
-I have the defendants.
And I have 23 Marines and a lieutenant
with four letters of commendation.
-Why did Markinson go U.A.?
-We'll never know.
-I can't subpoena Markinson?
-You won't find him.
You know what Markinson did
for 17 years? Counterintelligence.
Markinson's gone.
There is no Markinson.
Look, Danny,
Jessep's star is on the rise.
Division will give me room to spare him
and the Corps any embarrassment.
How much room?
I'll knock it down to involuntary
manslaughter. Two years.
No, we're going to court.
-No, you're not.
-Why not?
Because you'll lose,
and Danny knows it.
And he knows if we go to court,
I'll have to go all the way.
They'll be charged
with the whole truckload.
Murder, conspiracy,
conduct unbecoming.
Danny's got me by the balls here,
but not in the courtroom.
Danny's an awfully talented lawyer.
He won't see his clients go jail for life
if they could be home in six months.
That's the end of this negotiation.
I'll see you at the arraignment.
All right, here's the story.
The government's offering
involuntary manslaughter. Two years.
You'll be home in six months.
“Wow! You're the greatest lawyer in
the world! How can we thank you?”
Fellas, you hear what I just said?
You'll be home in six months.
I'm afraid we can't do that, sir.
Do what?
-Make a deal, sir.
-What are you talking about?
We did nothing wrong. We did our job.
If that has consequences,
I'll accept them.
But I won't say that I'm guilty, sir.
-Did she put you up to this?
-No.
We have a code, sir.
You and your code plead not guilty.
You'll be in jail for life.
Do what I say,
and you'll be home in six months.
Do it, Harold. Six months, it's nothing.
It's a hockey season.
-Permission to--
-Speak! Jesus!
-What do we do then, sir?
-When?
After six months we'll be
dishonorably discharged, right, sir?
-Probably.
-What do we do then, sir?
We joined the Marines because
we wanted to live by a certain code.
You're asking us to say we have no
honor, that we're not Marines!
If a court decides what we did
was wrong, I'll accept my punishment.
But I believe I was right. I did my job.
I will not dishonor myself, my unit...
...or the Corps,
so that I can go home in six months!
Sir!
I'd like to talk to
Lance Corporal Dawson...
...alone for a minute, please.
Sergeant!
-We'd like to go to another room.
-Sit down.
You don't like me very much,
do you?
Forget it, don't answer that.
It doesn't matter.
You know, Downey worships you.
He's gonna do whatever you do.
Are you really gonna let this happen
to him because of a code, Harold?
-Do you think we were right?
-Doesn't matter--
Do you think we were right?!
I think you'd lose.
You're such a coward.
I can't believe they let you
wear a uniform.
I'm not gonna feel responsible for this.
I did all I could.
You're going to Leavenworth
for the better part of your life...
...and I don't give a shit.
What happened to saluting
an officer when he leaves the room?
Open it up.
I don't believe it!
He's gonna go to jail to spite me!
If he wants to jump off a cliff,
that's his business.
I'm not gonna hold his hand.
-How do I get him a new lawyer?
-Make a motion at the arraignment.
Just tell the judge
you want new counsel assigned.
That's that.
One thing, though.
When you ask the judge...
...be sure and ask nicely.
-What do you want from me?
-I want you to make an argument.
That didn't help Calley at My Lai,
or the Nazis at Nuremburg.
For chrissakes, Sam.
Do you think that's the same...
...as two teenagers executing an
order they didn't think would harm?
These guys aren't Nazis.
Don't look now,
but you're making an argument.
Yeah, yeah. Tomorrow morning,
I get them a new attorney.
Why are you so afraid to be a lawyer?
You Daddy's expectations that high?
Please, spare me
the psychobabble father bullshit!
They'll have their day in court,
but with another lawyer.
Another lawyer won't be good enough.
They need you. You know how to win.
You know they have a case. You walk
away from this, you seal their fate.
Their fate was sealed
the moment Santiago died.
Do you believe they have a case?
You and Dawson, you both
live in the same dream world.
It doesn't matter what I believe,
it only matters what I can prove.
So don't tell me what I know
and don't know. I know the law!
You know nothing about the law.
You're a used-car salesman.
An ambulance-chaser with a rank.
You're nothing. Live with that.
So I told Duncan:
“If you wanna take this to court, you'll
force me to file discovery motions...
...and you're gonna spend a year
going blind on paperwork...
...because a 90-year-old man
misread the Delaware insurance code.”
-So, what happened?
-Fifteen minutes later, he makes a deal.
All rise.
-Where are we?
-Docket number 411275 VR-5.
The United States v.
Lance Corporal Harold Dawson...
...and Private First Class
Louden Downey.
The accused are charged with murder,
conspiracy to commit murder...
...and conduct unbecoming
a United States Marine.
Does the defense
wish to enter a plea?
Yeah.
They're not guilty.
Enter a plea of “not guilty”
for the accused.
We will adjourn until 10:00, three weeks
from today, when we will reconvene.
Why does a lieutenant
with nine months' experience...
...and a record for plea-bargaining
get assigned a murder case?
Would it be so that it never sees
the inside of a courtroom?
We'll work out of my apartment.
Jo, bring legal pads and pens.
Sam, get a couple desk lamps.
I need you to start a medical profile.
Jo, get Dawson's, Downey's
and Santiago's conduct reports.
I've only got Yoo-hoo and Cocoa Puffs,
so if you want anything else, bring it.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
So this is what a courtroom looks like.
-You speak to your friend at the NIS?
-Yeah.
She said if Markinson doesn't
want to be found, we won't find him.
She said I could be Markinson,
and you wouldn't know it.
-Are you Markinson?
-No.
I'm not Markinson.
That's two down.
What?
I'm just wondering,
now that Joanne's on this...
I'm just wondering if you still need me.
-They were following orders, Sam.
-An illegal order.
You think Dawson and Downey
knew it was illegal?
It doesn't matter.
Any decent human would have--
They're not permitted
to question orders.
Then what's the secret?
I give orders every day, nobody obeys!
We have softball and marching bands.
They work at a place where you have to
wear camouflage or you might get shot.
I need you.
You're better at research than I am.
And you know
how to prepare a witness.
I've got medical reports
and Chinese food. I say we eat first.
What?
Did you get any kung pao chicken?
This is our defense. Intent.
No one can prove there was poison.
Code Red. They're common
and accepted in Guantánamo Bay.
The order. A, Kendrick gave it,
B, they had no choice but to follow.
-What about motive?
-We're weak. They had one.
That doesn't make them guilty.
Relax. We'll deal with that later.
For now, we start with intent.
We must show that Santiago could've
died from something other than poison.
Jo, find out all about
lactic acidosis.
This is Lt. Commander Galloway
with the JAG Corps.
I've been trying to track down
a Lt. Colonel Matthew Markinson....
Doctor, was there any sign
of external damage?
No scrapes? No cuts?
Bruises? Broken bones?
Was there any sign of violence?
-Other than the dead body?
-Shit. I walk into that every time.
He ordered me and Dawson
to give Willy a Code Red.
Answers still have to come faster.
This farm boy thing
will play for a while...
...but in the end, it sounds like
he's searching for it.
Right. And Willy is Private Santiago.
Willy is someone with a mother.
They drew court members.
Seven men, two women.
All experienced officers.
The women have no children.
That's a bad break.
My father said a jury trial
is about assigning blame.
Santiago's dead and he shouldn't be.
They want to know who's to blame.
Ross hands them our clients,
we hand them Kendrick.
This won't be won by the law,
but by the lawyers. So, poker faces.
Don't flinch. If something goes wrong,
don't hang your head or scribble.
Whatever happens, you have to
look like you expected it.
-You pass me documents--
-”Swiftly, and don't look overanxious.”
Don't wear that perfume in court,
wrecks my concentration.
-Really?
-I was talking to Sam.
-What time is it?
-It's time to go home. Try to sleep.
-Give me a ride?
-Sure.
-You're a good man, Charlie Brown.
-I'll see you in court, counselor.
-Danny, I--
-I know. We've had our differences.
We both said things we didn't mean.
But you're happy I stuck with the case.
If you've gained some respect for me,
well, of course I'm happy about that.
But it's no big deal.
You like me, I won't make you say it.
I was just gonna tell you
to wear matching socks tomorrow.
Okay. Good tip.
-We're ready.
-You'd better believe it.
We're gonna get creamed.
Lieutenant Kaffee.
You are gonna save our son,
aren't you?
I'll do my best.
Danny, I'd like you to meet
Ginny Miller, Louden's aunt.
You're Aunt Ginny?
-I was expecting someone older.
-So was I.
-Last chance. I'll flip you for it.
-All rise.
Too late.
All those having business with this
court-martial, stand forward.
Colonel Julius Alexander Randolph
is presiding.
Is the government prepared
to make an opening statement?
The facts of the case are these:
On September 6th, the accused
entered PFC Santiago's room.
They woke him up,
tied his arms and legs...
...and forced a rag into his throat.
Minutes later, a reaction called lactic
acidosis caused his lungs to bleed.
He drowned in his own blood, and
was dead at 37 minutes past midnight.
These are the facts of the case,
and they are undisputed.
That's right. What I've just told you
is exactly what you will hear...
...from Lance Corporal Dawson
and Private Downey.
Furthermore, we will also show that
the accused soaked the rag in poison...
...and entered Santiago's room
with motive and intent to kill.
Lieutenant Kaffee is gonna try
and pull off a little magic act here.
He'll try a little misdirection.
He'll astonish you
with stories of rituals.
Dazzle you with official-sounding
terms like “Code Red.”
He might even try to cut
into a few officers for you.
He'll have no evidence, none,
but it'll be entertaining.
But in the end...
...all the magic in the world will not
divert your attention from the fact...
...that Willy Santiago is dead,
and Dawson and Downey killed him.
These are the facts of the case,
and they are undisputed.
Lieutenant Kaffee.
There was no poison on the rag
and there was no intent to kill...
...and any attempt to prove otherwise
is futile, because it just ain't true.
Dawson and Downey didn't go
into Santiago's room...
...because of vengeance.
It wasn't to kill or harm.
And they weren't looking for kicks.
It's because it was what
they were ordered to do.
Let me say that again.
It's because they were ordered to do it.
Out in the real world,
that means nothing.
And here in the Washington
Navy Yard...
...doesn't mean a whole lot more.
But if you're a Marine...
...assigned to Rifle Security Company
Windward, Guantánamo Bay, Cuba...
...you follow orders,
or you pack your bags.
Make no mistake about it.
Dawson and Downey are sitting here...
...because they did their job.
Is the government ready to
call its first witness?
Please the court,
government calls Mr. R.C. Mc.Guire.
Raise your right hand, please.
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole
truth, and nothing but the truth?
-I do.
-Have a seat, please.
Would you state
your full name and occupation?
Robert C. Mc.Guire, special agent,
Naval Investigative Service.
Did you receive a letter from PFC
Santiago on 3 September of this year?
-We did.
-What did it say?
That a member of Santiago's unit
had illegally fired across the fenceline.
Was that Marine identified in the letter?
No. I told Colonel Jessep that I
would be coming down to investigate.
And what did you find?
The shift reported only one sentry
returned his weapon...
...with ammo missing.
-Who was that?
-Lance Corporal Harold Dawson.
Your Witness.
Mr. McGuire, have you questioned
Dawson about the shooting?
Yes, he claims to have been engaged
in some manner by the enemy.
-But you don't believe him?
-It's not my place--
Why wasn't Dawson charged with
firing at the enemy without cause?
There wasn't enough evidence
to support such a charge.
Thank you.
Why was there not enough evidence?
You had William Santiago's letter.
Santiago was the only eyewitness.
I had no chance to interview him.
And now we'll never know,
will we, Mr. McGuire?
No.
-No more questions.
-The witness is excused.
Corporal Carl Hammaker,
Marine barracks...
...Rifle Security Company Windward,
2nd Platoon Bravo.
Were you present at a meeting...
...held by Lieutenant Kendrick
on September 6th?
-Yes, sir.
-What was the substance of it?
Lieutenant Kendrick told us
we had an informer in our group.
That Santiago had reported to
the NIS on a member of our platoon.
Did that make you mad?
-You can tell the truth. Did it?
-Yes, sir.
How mad?
Santiago betrayed a code
we believe in.
-Were other men also angry?
-Object. Speculation.
Were Dawson and Downey?
Is the counsel asking this witness
to testify...
...as to how my clients felt
on Sept. 6th?
Sustained.
Did Lieutenant Kendrick leave
a standing order at that meeting?
-Yes, sir.
-What was it?
It was clear he didn't want us
taking matters into our own hands.
-What was the order?
-Santiago wasn't to be touched.
Your witness.
Were you in Dawson and Downey's
room five minutes later?
No, sir.
-Thanks. No more questions.
-The witness is excused.
Government calls
Corporal Raymond Thomas.
Captain Ross is planning to call all
the members of the platoon to testify.
In light of the defense
Kaffee is planning...
...the platoon leader's instructions
seems relevant testimony.
The defense concedes that all 22
will confirm Hammaker's account...
...if the government concedes
none of them...
...were in Dawson and Downey's room
at 1620.
-Captain?
-The government will stipulate.
Then we will adjourn. You can
call your next witness tomorrow.
All rise.
-Let's go over the doctor again.
-It's the right approach.
We've been over this already.
At 3:00, Stone says he doesn't know
what killed Santiago.
Then he meets with Jessep, and at
5:00 he says it was poison? He's lying.
That's a relief.
I was afraid I couldn't use
the “liar, liar, pants on fire” defense.
We can't prove coercion.
Let's go over what we have.
Private Santiago was
admitted to the ER at 00:12...
...and he was pronounced dead
at 00:37.
Dr. Stone, what is lactic acidosis?
If the muscles and other cells
burn sugar instead of oxygen...
...lactic acid is produced.
That lactic acid is what caused
Santiago's lungs to bleed.
How long does it take before
the muscles start burning sugar?
-Twenty to 30 minutes.
-What made it faster with Santiago?
-An ingested poison of some kind.
-Object. The witness is speculating.
He is an expert medical witness.
In this court,
his opinion is not speculation.
He is not a criminologist.
The medical facts are inconclusive.
A point I'm confident you'll illustrate
on your cross-examination.
So I'm sure you won't mind
if his opinion is admitted now?
Not at all, sir.
-Did Willy Santiago die of poisoning?
-Absolutely.
You're aware that the lab and coroner's
reports show no traces of poison?
-Yes, I am.
-Then how do you justify--?
There are literally dozens of toxins
which are virtually undetectable.
The nature of the acidosis
is the compelling factor here.
Thank you, sir.
Commander, is it possible for a person
to have an affliction, some condition...
...which might also speed up acidosis?
-Is it possible?
-It's possible.
What might
some of those conditions be?
If a person had a coronary
or cerebral disorder...
...the process would be more rapid.
If I had a coronary condition...
...and a perfectly clean rag was placed
in my mouth and pushed too far...
...is it possible my cells would continue
burning sugar...
...after the rag was taken out?
It would have to be
a very serious condition.
Is it possible to have
a serious condition...
...where initial symptoms
were so mild...
...as to escape a physician
during a routine medical exam?
Possibly.
There would still be symptoms.
What kind of symptoms?
-There are hundreds of--
-Chest pains?
-Yes. Yes.
-Shortness of breath? Fatigue?
Of course.
-Doctor, is this your signature?
-Yes, it is.
This is an order for Private Santiago
to be put on restricted duty.
Would you read your handwritten
remarks at the bottom of the page?
“Patient complains of chest pains,
shortness of breath, and fatigue.
Restricted from running distances
over five miles for one week.”
Isn't it possible Santiago had
a serious coronary condition...
...and it was that condition,
not poison...
...that caused
the rapid chemical reaction?
-No.
-It's not possible?
No. I personally give each man
a thorough physical examination.
Private Santiago was given
a clean bill of health.
That's why it had to be poison, right?
Because if you gave a man
with a serious condition...
...a clean bill of health and he died
from a heart-related incident...
...you'd have a lot to answer for.
-Object! Move to strike!
-Sustained.
I have no more questions, Your Honor.
You've held a license
to practice medicine for 17 years.
You're certified in internal medicine,
you're chief of internal medicine...
...at a hospital which has served
5426 people.
In your professional opinion,
was Willy Santiago poisoned?
We ask that the doctor's testimony
be stricken from the record.
-The court should disregard it.
-The objection's overruled.
We strenuously object,
and requests an 802 conference...
...so His Honor can hear discussion
before ruling on this objection.
-The objection has been overruled.
-Move to reconsider.
Noted. The witness is an expert,
and the court will hear his opinion!
In your expert professional opinion,
was Willy Santiago poisoned?
-Yes.
-Thank you, sir. No more questions.
You may step down.
While we reserve the right to call
rebuttal witnesses, government rests.
We'll recess until Monday the 19th...
...when the defense
will call its first witness.
All rise.
“I strenuously object”?
Is that how it works?
“Objection.” “Overruled!”
“No, I strenuously object!”
-”Oh, then I'll reconsider!”
-I got it on the record.
You got the court thinking
we're afraid of the doctor.
You object once, so we can say
he's not a criminologist.
You keep after it, our cross looks like
a bunch of fancy lawyer tricks.
It's the difference between
paper law and trial law!
-The judge called him an expert!
-Sam, she made a mistake.
Let's not relive it.
I'm gonna go call my wife.
I'll see you tonight.
-Why do you hate them so much?
-They beat up on a weakling.
The rest is this just
smoke-filled-coffeehouse crap.
They tortured and tormented
a weaker kid!
They didn't like him, so they killed him.
Why?
Because he couldn't run very fast!
-Everybody take the night off.
-I'm sorry...
We've been working 20 hours a day.
Go see your wife and daughter.
Jo, go do.... Whatever it is you do
when you're not here.
-What day is tomorrow?
-Saturday.
We'll start at 10.
Why do you like them so much?
Because they stand on a wall and say,
“Nothing's gonna hurt you tonight.
Not on my watch.”
Don't worry about the doctor.
This trial starts Monday.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I should have called first.
No, I was just watching the ball game.
Come on in.
I was wondering how you'd feel
if I took you to dinner tonight?
-Are you asking me out on a date?
-No.
-It sounded like you were.
-I wasn't.
I've been asked out before,
and that's what it sounded like.
Do you like seafood?
I know a good seafood place.
Okay.
My third case was a “drunk
and disorderly”. It lasted nine weeks.
I rounded up 31 people
from the bar that night.
Nine weeks on a D and D?
What was the prosecutor offering?
Fifteen days.
You sure hustled the shit out of him.
After that, I got shifted
to Internal Affairs.
Tough to blame them.
Where I have earned two medals
and two letters of commendation.
Why are you always
giving me your résumé?
-I want you to think I'm a good lawyer.
-I do.
No, you don't.
I think you're an exceptional lawyer.
The court members respond to you.
I see you convince them. Dawson
and Downey will owe you their lives.
Jo, I think....
I think you should prepare yourself
for the fact we're gonna lose.
Ross's opening statement was all true.
Let's pretend it would matter
to the court...
...that the guys were given an order.
I can't prove it ever happened.
We'll keep doing what we're doing
and put on a show...
...but all we have is the testimony of
two people accused of murder.
-We'll find Markinson.
-Jo, we're gonna lose, and lose huge.
Corporal Barnes, Windward Barracks,
Guantánamo Bay, Cuba.
Name some reasons why a Marine
would receive a Code Red.
Being late for platoon
or company meetings...
...keeping barracks in disorder,
falling back on a run....
-Have you ever received a Code Red?
-Yes, sir.
I dropped my weapon in a drill.
It was over 100 degrees. My palms
were sweaty and I hadn't used resin.
-What happened?
-The guys threw a blanket over me.
They punched me on the arms
and poured glue on my hands.
And it worked.
I ain't never dropped my weapon since.
-Was Private Santiago ever late?
-Yes, sir.
-Was his barracks ever in disorder?
-Did he ever fall back on a run?
-All the time.
Did he ever, prior to September 6th,
receive a Code Red?
No, sir.
-Never?
-No, sir.
You got a Code Red because
your palms were sweaty.
Why didn't Santiago,
this burden to his unit, ever get one?
-Dawson wouldn't allow it, sir.
-Dawson wouldn't allow it.
The guys talked tough about Santiago,
but they were too afraid of Dawson.
Object. Witness is speculating.
Did you want to give Santiago
a Code Red?
Yes, sir.
-Why didn't you?
-Because Dawson would kick my butt.
Good enough. Captain Ross is gonna
will ask you some questions.
Corporal Barnes...
...I hold here the Marine Recruit
Outline. Are you familiar with it?
-Have you read it? Good.
-Yes, sir.
Turn to the chapter that deals
with Code Reds, please.
-Sir?
-Just flip to the page with Code Reds.
Well, “Code Red” is a term that we use
down at Gitmo. I don't know if it's--
Oh, we're in luck, then.
“Standard Operating Procedure,
Rifle Security Company...
...Guantánamo Bay, Cuba.”
I assume we'll find “Code Red”
in there?
-No, sir.
-No?
I'm a Marine. Is there no book,
no set of orders or regulations...
...telling me that one of my duties
is to perform Code Reds?
No, sir. No book, sir.
No further questions.
Would you turn to the page that says
where the mess hall is, please?
Lieutenant Kaffee,
that's not in the book, sir.
-You mean you've never had a meal?
-No, sir. Three squares a day, sir.
I don't understand. How did you find
the mess hall if it's not in this book?
-I guess I just followed the crowd.
-No more questions.
-Corporal Barnes, you may step down.
-Thank you, sir.
Seven tonight,
we'll do a final Kendrick review.
I wanna slam-dunk this guy.
-Hey, Luther.
-Admiral! How's the big case going?
-Nose to the grindstone.
-No flies on you.
Rolling stone gathers no moss.
Well, it ain't over till the fat lady sings.
You can say that again.
-It ain't over till the fat lady sings.
-Till the fat lady sings.
I walked into that one.
-Jesus Christ!
-You left the door unlocked.
-You scared the shit out of me.
-Just keep driving.
Are you aware you're under subpoena?
Yes. I'm also aware the lives
of two Marines are in your hands.
If I could do something about that,
I would.
Since I can't, all I can do is help you.
-What do you know?
-I know everything.
-Was it a Code Red?
-Yes.
-Did Kendrick give the order?
Did you witness it? Did you witness it?
-No.
-Then how do you know?
-I know.
-Yeah, you know shit.
He was never gonna be transferred
off that base.
Jessep was gonna keep him on
the base, said he wanted him “trained.”
-You signed the transfer order.
-Yeah, I know.
I signed them when you got to Cuba,
five days after Santiago's death.
I'll get you immunity. In about four days
you can tell the court what you told me.
Right now I'll check you into a motel.
We're gonna start from the beginning.
I don't want a deal,
and I don't want immunity.
I'm not proud of what I have done,
nor of what I am doing.
-Where is he?
-The Downtown Lodge.
-I want him guarded.
-That's a good idea.
-My clearance code is 4115273.
-Clearance code?
I don't have a clearance code. You?
It's Galloway.
I need to secure a witness.
He also said Jessep's lying about
transportation off the base.
Jessep said that 6 the next morning
was the first flight.
Markinson says there was one
that left seven hours earlier.
-That was impressive. You hear that?
-Yeah.
Sam, isn't there a record of flights?
You need the tower chief's log
from Gitmo.
-Get it.
-We're gonna win.
Jo, don't get crazy. We don't
know Markinson, or the log book.
You concentrate on Downey,
I'll talk to Ross.
Hey, Danny. Nice work today.
The redirect on Barnes.
-I have Markinson.
-Where is he?
Motel room in Northeast, six marshals
outside the door. Take a sip.
The transfer Markinson signed
is phony.
And Jessep lied about the first flight.
We're getting the log.
-Can I get you something?
-Beer.
In the meantime,
I'm gonna put Kendrick on the stand...
...and have some fun.
If you accuse Kendrick or Jessep
of any crime without evidence...
...you'll be court-martialled
for misconduct...
...and that's gonna be stapled to
every job application you ever fill out.
Markinson won't hold up,
he's a crazy man.
I'm not saying this to intimidate you,
I'm being your lawyer here.
Thanks. And I wanna tell you I think the
whole fucking bunch of you are insane.
This code of honor makes me
wanna beat someone!
Don't you dare lump me in
with Kendrick and Jessep.
I'm your friend. Your clients don't
belong in jail, but it's not my decision.
I represent the U.S. government
without passion or prejudice...
-...and my client has a case.
-Here you go.
I want you to acknowledge that the
judge advocate has made you aware...
...of the consequences of accusing
a Marine officer without evidence.
I've been so advised.
You got bullied into that courtroom.
By everyone. By Dawson. By Galloway.
Shit, I practically dared you.
You got bullied into that courtroom
by the memory of a dead lawyer.
You're a lousy fucking
softball player, Jack!
Your boys are going down, Danny.
I can't stop it anymore.
-Was Santiago a good Marine?
-I'd say he was average.
Your proficiency and conduct reports
all indicate he was below average.
Yes, he was below average.
I did not see the need
to trample on his grave.
We appreciate it,
but you're under oath.
I think we'd all like to hear the truth.
I'm aware of my oath.
These are the last three
pro-con reports you signed...
...for Lance Corporal Dawson.
He rated exceptional twice,
but on June 9th he's below average.
-I'd like to discuss that.
-That would be fine.
Dawson's ranking after
the School of Infantry was perfect.
But unlike most of his class,
he hasn't been promoted.
-Was this report the reason?
-I'm sure it was.
-Do you recall why he got this grade?
-I'm sure I don't.
I have many men in my charge.
I write many reports.
Do you recall an incident
involving a PFC Curtis Bell...
...stealing liquor
from the officers' club?
Yes, I do.
Did you report Private Bell
to the proper authorities?
I have two books at my bedside:
the Marine Code
and the King James Bible.
The only proper authorities I'm
aware of are Colonel Jessep and God.
Then you don't recognize this court
as a proper authority?
-Objection. Argumentative.
-Sustained. Watch yourself.
-Did you report Private Bell?
-I thought very highly of him.
I didn't want his record tarnished
by a charge.
You preferred it be handled in the unit?
Yes, I most certainly did.
-Do you know what a Code Red is?
-Yes, I do.
-Have you ever ordered one?
-No, I have not.
Did you order that Private Bell receive
no food or drink except water...
...for a period of seven days?
You're distorting the truth.
He was on barracks restriction.
He was given water and vitamins.
His health was never in danger.
I'm sure it was lovely for him.
But you did order the restriction.
-You denied him food?
-Yes, I did.
-Wouldn't this be called a Code Red?
-No.
Would the other 478 Marines
at Guantánamo...
...consider it a Code Red?
The witness can't testify as to
what 478 other men would say.
These questions are argumentative,
and irrelevant badgering of the witness.
Sustained. And I would remind you...
...that you're questioning an officer
with an impeccable service record.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Was Dawson rated below average
for sneaking food to Private Bell?
-Object!
-Not so fast. Lieutenant?
Dawson was given a below average
rating for committing a crime.
Crime? What crime did he commit?
Lieutenant Kendrick, Dawson
brought a hungry guy some food.
-What crime did he commit?
-He disobeyed an order.
And because he made a decision about
the welfare of a Marine...
...that conflicted with your order,
he was punished, right?
Lance Corporal Dawson
disobeyed an order!
It wasn't a real order, was it?
After all, it's peacetime.
He wasn't asked
to advance on a beachhead.
Surely a Marine
of Dawson's intelligence...
...can be trusted to
distinguish important orders...
...from those that might be
morally questionable?
Lieutenant Kendrick? Can he?
Can Dawson determine on his own
which orders to follow?
No, he cannot.
A lesson he learned
after the Bell incident.
-I would think so.
-You know so, don't you?
-Object!
-Sustained.
Lieutenant Kendrick,
one final question.
If you had ordered Dawson
to give Santiago a Code Red...
-I ordered them not to touch him!
-...would he dare disobey you again?
-Lieutenant, don't answer that!
-You don't have to. I'm through.
Did you order Dawson and Downey
to give Willy Santiago a Code Red?
-Lieutenant Kendrick, did you--?
-No, I did not.
-What's the word?
-Well...
...I got the tower chief's log.
Jessep's telling the truth.
-Six a.m. flight was the first plane.
-Let me see this.
-Working late tonight, lieutenant?
-Oh, yeah.
There was no flight at 11:00!
What the fuck are you trying to pull?!
The first flight left at 23:00.
It arrived at Andrews at 2 a.m.
Really? Then why isn't it listed
in the tower chief's log?
-Jessep.
-What? He fixed the logbook?
Maybe he can make it so it didn't
take off, but I can prove it landed.
I'll get the logbook from Andrews.
-You won't find anything.
-He can make a flight disappear?
Nathan Jessep is
about to be appointed...
...to the National Security Council.
You don't get there without knowing
how to sidestep a few landmines.
He won't be able to sidestep you.
You still intend
to put me on the stand?
Thursday morning. Ten o'clock.
There's gotta be someone
who can testify to the flight.
This isn't TWA. You know how many
planes take off and land every day?
The ground crew isn't gonna
remember it.
Well, how do you know--
Forget the flight. Forget the flight.
Markinson will testify that
the transfer was forged.
That and Downey's testimony
really ought to be enough.
Why did you go into Santiago's room
on the night of the 6th?
-To give him a Code Red.
-And why did you do that?
I was ordered to
by the platoon commander...
...Lieutenant
Jonathan James Kendrick.
You're gonna do fine.
-Think we can rejoin the platoon soon?
-Absolutely.
Remember the order of the questions?
Are you sure? And use small words.
-Just go slow.
-I'm gonna go slow.
Okay. And get him off
as fast as you can.
What? It's gonna be fine.
Dear Mr. and Mrs. Santiago,
l was William's executive officer.
I knew your son vaguely,
which is to say I knew his name.
Soon, the trial of the two men charged
with his death will be concluded...
...and the jury will try to offer you
an explanation as to why he's dead.
For my part, I've done as much
as I can to bring the truth to light.
And the truth is this:
Your son is dead for only one reason...
...I wasn't strong enough to stop it.
Always, Lieutenant Colonel
Matthew Andrew Markinson...
...United States Marine Corps.
Private, I want you to tell us
one last time:
Why did you go to Santiago's room
on the night of September 6th?
A Code Red was ordered
by Platoon Commander Kendrick.
Thank you. Your witness.
The week of 2 September,
the switch log...
...has you down at Post 39
until 16:00. Right?
-They keep that log pretty good.
-How far is Post 39 from barracks?
-It's a ways, sir. It's a hike.
-About how far by jeep?
About 10, 15 minutes, sir.
-You ever had to walk it?
-Yes, sir, that day. Friday.
The pickup private-- That's what
we call the guy that drops us off.
Also because he can get the girls
in New York City.
--he got a flat tire at Post 39,
so we had to jog back to barracks.
And if it's 10 or 15 minutes by jeep,
it must be an hour by foot, right?
-We did it in 45 flat, sir.
-Not bad.
You've said your assault on Santiago
was ordered by Lieutenant Kendrick...
...in your barracks room at 16:20,
am I right?
Yes, sir.
You said you weren't back
before 16:45.
Sir?
If you weren't back till 16:45...
...how could you be in your room
at 16:20?
Well, you see, sir,
there was a blow-out....
Did you ever actually hear...
...Lieutenant Kendrick order
a Code Red?
Well, Hal said that--
Did you ever actually hear...
...Lieutenant Kendrick order
a Code Red?
-No, sir.
-I'd like to request a recess.
-The witness has rights!
-He has been read his rights.
The question will be repeated.
Why did you go to Santiago's room?
Did Dawson tell you to?
-Don't look at him!
-Answer the captain's question.
Yes. I was given an order by
Lance Corporal Dawson...
...and I followed it.
Where do you think he is?
As far as Downey was concerned,
it was an order from Kendrick.
It doesn't matter that
he didn't hear firsthand.
-Danny, I'm sorry.
-Don't worry about it.
All we need to do is call
some witnesses...
...to talk about implied orders...
...or call Downey back before
we get to Dawson.
Maybe we could get Dawson charged
with the Kennedy assassination?
-Are you drunk?
-Pretty much. Yeah.
I'll put on a pot of coffee.
We've got a long night's work ahead.
She's gonna make coffee?
That's nice.
Downey wasn't in his room.
He wasn't even there.
That was important information,
don't you think?
Danny, it was a setback.
And I'm sorry.
But we fix it and move on to Markinson.
Markinson's dead.
You really got to hand it
to those federal marshals, boy.
He didn't hang himself
by his shoelaces...
...or slash his wrists
with a butter knife.
This guy got into full dress uniform,
drew a nickel-plated pistol...
...and fired a bullet into his mouth.
Anyway, since we're out of witnesses,
I thought I'd drink a little.
-I still think we can win.
-Maybe you should drink a little.
In the morning, we'll ask Randolph
for a continuance, 24 hours.
-Why would we do that?
-To subpoena Colonel Jessep.
-What?
-Listen for a second.
No! I won't listen.
Your passion is compelling,
but useless.
Louden Downey
needed a trial lawyer today.
You chickenshit.
You just want an excuse to give up.
It's over.
Why did you ask Jessep
for the transfer order?
-In Cuba, why did you ask him?
-What does it matter?
-I wanted the damn transfer order!
-Bullshit!
You could have gotten it by calling
any one of a dozen departments.
You didn't want the order.
You wanted to see Jessep's reaction.
You had an instinct
and it was confirmed by Markinson.
Now let's put Jessep on the stand
and end this thing.
-What possible good would that do?
-He ordered the Code Red.
He did? That's great!
And of course, you have proof?
I'm sorry, I forgot.
You were sick that day at law school.
You put him on the stand
and get it from him.
We get it from him!
Yes, no problem. We get it from him.
Colonel Jessep, isn't it true you
ordered the Code Red on Santiago?
I'm sorry, time's run out!
What do we have for the losers, judge?
“Well, for the defendants,
it's life at exotic Fort Leavenworth!
And for Defense Counsel Kaffee,
that's right, it's a court-martial!
After falsely accusing a decorated
officer of conspiracy and perjury...
...Lieutenant Kaffee will have
a long and prosperous career...
...teaching typewriter maintenance
at a women's school!
Thank you for playing Follow the
Advice of the Galactically Stupid!”
I'm sorry I lost you
your set of steak knives.
Stop cleaning up.
Sam, stop cleaning up.
-You want a drink?
-Yeah.
-Is your father proud of you?
-Don't do this to yourself.
I'll bet he is.
I'll bet he bores the shit out of
the neighbors and relatives.
“Sam's made law review.
He's got a big case he's making.
He's making an argument.”
I think my father would have enjoyed
seeing me graduate from law school.
I think he would have liked that a lot.
I ever tell you I wrote a paper
about your father in college?
Yeah?
-One of the best trial lawyers ever.
-Yes, he was.
But if I were Dawson and Downey,
and had to choose you or him...
...I'd choose you any day of the week,
and twice on Sunday.
You should have seen yourself
thunder away at Kendrick.
-Would you put Jessep on the stand?
-No.
Do you think my father would have?
-With the evidence we got?
Not in a million years.
But here's the thing,
and we can't get around this:
Neither Lionel Kaffee nor
Sam Weinberg...
...are lead counsel for the defense
in U.S. v. Dawson and Downey.
So there's really only one question:
What would you do?
Jo. Joanne! Jo, get in the car.
Joanne, please get in the car! Look....
JoAnne! I apologize. I was angry.
I'm sorry about what I said.
I'm gonna put Jessep on the stand!
What do you suggest we do?
Hit Jessep with
the phony transfer order.
-Without a witness?
-We have a witness.
A dead witness.
To a lesser attorney,
that'd be a problem.
Look. Last night he's swimming in
Jack Daniel's, today he's Superman!
I'm getting my second wind.
Sit down, both of you. Good.
Jessep told Kendrick to order
the Code Red...
...Kendrick did,
our clients followed orders.
The cover-up isn't our case. To win,
Jessep has to say he gave the order.
-And you can get him to say it?
-I think he wants to say it!
I think he's pissed off he's gotta hide.
I think he wants to say...
...he made a decision,
and that's the end of it!
He eats breakfast 300 yards from 4000
Cubans that are trained to kill him.
And no one tells him
how to run his unit...
...least of all the Harvard mouth
in his faggoty white uniform.
I need to shake him. I'll lead him
right where he's dying to go.
-That's it? That's the plan?
-That's the plan.
How are you going to do it?
-I have no idea. I need my bat.
-Your what?
I need my bat. I think better with it.
Where is it?
-I put it in the closet.
-You put it in the closet?
I was tripping on it.
Don't ever put that bat in the closet.
Stay here.
I'm going to the office for a while.
He does think better with that bat.
-Hello?
-Sam, I need you to do something.
-What's going on?
-Gotta go out to Andrews.
-Did Sam get the guys?
-Yes.
-Can I talk to you for a second?
-Yeah, sure.
How are you feeling?
Well, I think Jessep's
gonna have his hands full today.
Listen, Danny,
when you're out there today...
...if you feel like it's not gonna happen,
like he's not going to say it...
...don't go for it.
You could get into trouble.
I'm special counsel for Internal Affairs.
I'm telling you you could get in trouble.
You're not suggesting that I
back off a material witness?
If you think you can't get him, yeah.
All rise!
-Where's Sam?
-He's on his way.
Call your first witness.
-Where is he?
-He'll be here. Don't worry.
Lieutenant! Call your witness.
Defense calls Colonel Nathan Jessep.
Colonel Jessep,
raise your right hand, please, sir.
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole
truth, and nothing but the truth?
-Yes, I do.
-Have a seat please, sir.
State your name, rank
and current billet for the record.
Colonel Jessep, Commanding Officer,
Marine Ground Forces...
...Guantánamo Bay, Cuba.
-Thank you, sir.
-He's not here.
When you learned
of Santiago's letter to the NIS...
...you had a meeting with
your two senior officers, is that right?
Yes.
Platoon Commander Kendrick...
...and the executive officer,
Lieutenant Colonel Markinson.
Yes.
And, at present,
Markinson is dead, is that right?
-What is the counselor implying?
-Simply that Markinson is not alive.
Surely Colonel Jessep
doesn't need to confirm that.
He may not be aware that Markinson
took his own life two days ago.
The witness, the court
and now the court members are aware.
We thank you for bringing it up.
Move on, lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
At this meeting,
you gave Kendrick an order, right?
I told him to tell his men
not to touch Santiago.
And did you give an order
to Markinson as well?
I ordered him to have Santiago
transferred off the base immediately.
-Why?
-I felt his life might be in danger.
-Grave danger?
-Is there another kind?
This is the transfer order
that you and Markinson co-signed...
...ordering that Santiago fly out
at 6 the next morning.
-Was that the first flight off the base?
-The 06:00 was the first flight.
-You flew here today, is that right?
-Yes.
-You're wearing your dress uniform.
-As are you, lieutenant.
-Did you wear it on the plane?
-Is this dialogue relevant to anything?
We didn't have a chance to depose.
I'd ask the court for a little latitude.
-A very little latitude.
-Colonel?
I wore utilities on the plane.
-You brought your dress uniform?
-Yes.
-Toothbrush, shaving kit, underwear?
-Your Honor!
Is his underwear
a matter of national security?
Gentlemen. You'd better get
somewhere fast with this, lieutenant.
Yes, sir. Colonel?
I brought a change of clothes
and some personal items.
Thank you.
After Dawson and Downey's arrest
on the night of the 6th...
...Santiago's barracks room was
sealed off, and its contents inventoried.
Four pairs of camouflage pants,
three khaki shirts, three pairs of boots.
-Four pairs green socks--
-Is there a question in our future?
Lieutenant, state your question.
I'm wondering why
Santiago wasn't packed.
Tell you what,
we'll get back to that one in a minute.
This is a record of all phone calls
from your base in the past 24 hours.
After being subpoenaed,
you made three calls.
Do you recognize those numbers?
I called Colonel Fitzhughes
to let him know I'd be in town.
The second was to arrange a meeting
with Congressman Richman.
-And the third call was to my sister.
-Why did you make that call?
-I thought she might like to have dinner.
-Your Honor.
I'll put a stop to this.
These are the phone records
from Gitmo for September 6th.
And these are 14 letters
that Santiago wrote in nine months...
...requesting, begging for a transfer.
Upon hearing the news
he was getting it...
...Santiago was so excited...
...you know how many people
he called? Zero! Nobody.
Not one call to his parents,
saying he was coming home.
Not one call to a friend,
saying, “Can you pick me up?”
He was asleep at midnight, and
you say he had a flight in six hours.
Yet everything he owned was
in his closet or his footlocker.
You were leaving for one day,
you packed and made three calls.
Santiago was leaving
for the rest of his life...
...and he hadn't called a soul,
and he hadn't packed a thing.
Can you explain that?
Fact is, there was no transfer order.
Santiago wasn't going anywhere, right?
Objection! Lieutenant Kaffee is trying to
smear a high-ranking Marine officer...
...desperately hoping to
suggest impropriety...
...and win points with the court.
I recommend that
he be reprimanded...
...and the witness be excused
with apologies.
-Overruled. The objection is noted.
-Colonel?
-Is this funny, sir?
-No, it's not. It's tragic.
-Do you have an answer?
-Absolutely. I don't have a damn clue.
Maybe he was an early riser.
Maybe he didn't have any friends.
I'm an educated man,
but I can't speak intelligently...
...about the travel habits
of William Santiago.
What I do know is that he was
set to leave the base at 06:00.
Now, are these really the questions
that I was called here to answer?
Phone calls and foot lockers?
Please tell me you have
something more, lieutenant.
These two Marines
are on trial for their lives.
Please tell me their lawyer hasn't
pinned their hopes to a phone bill.
Do you have any other questions
for me, counselor?
Lieutenant Kaffee?
Lieutenant, do you have anything
further for this witness?
-Thanks, Danny. I love Washington.
-Excuse me. I didn't dismiss you.
I beg your pardon?
-I'm not through with my examination.
Sit down.
-“Colonel.”
-What's that?
I'd appreciate if he would address me
as “colonel” or “sir.” I've earned it.
Defense counsel will address him
“colonel” or “sir”.
I don't know what the hell
kind of unit you're running here.
And the witness will address me
as “judge” or “Your Honor.”
I'm quite certain I've earned it.
Take your seat, colonel.
What shall we discuss now?
My favorite color?
Colonel, the 6 a.m. flight
was the first off the base?
Yes.
There wasn't one seven hours earlier
and landed at Andrews at 2 a.m.?
I think we've covered this,
haven't we?
These are the tower chief's logs for
Guantánamo Bay and Andrews.
There's no flight at 11 p.m.,
and no arrival at 2 a.m.
I'd like to admit them as
Defense Exhibits Alpha and Bravo.
You're admitting evidence of a flight
that never existed.
We believe it did, sir.
We call Airmen O'Malley and
Rodriguez of Andrews Air Base.
-They weren't on the list.
-They are rebuttal witnesses.
-I'll allow the witnesses.
-This is ridiculous!
Colonel, a moment ago--
-Check the logs, for chrissake!
-We'll get to that in a minute.
You said you ordered Kendrick to say
that Santiago wasn't to be touched.
That's right.
-He was clear on what you wanted?
-Crystal.
-Could he have ignored the order?
-Ignored the order?
-Or forgot about it?
-No.
Any chance he could have thought,
“The old man is wrong”?
No.
When Lt. Kendrick talked to the men,
any chance they ignored him?
-You ever served in the infantry, son?
-No, sir.
-Ever served in a forward area?
Ever put your life in another
man's hands, and his in yours?
No, sir.
We follow orders, son.
We follow orders or people die.
It's that simple. Are we clear?
Yes, sir.
-Are we clear?
-Crystal.
Just one more question, before I call
Airmen O'Malley and Rodriguez.
If you ordered that Santiago wasn't
to be touched...
...and your orders
are always followed...
...then why would Santiago
be in danger?
Why would it be necessary
to transfer him off the base?
Santiago was a substandard Marine.
He was being transferred--
You said he was being transferred
because he was in grave danger.
-That's correct.
-You said he was in danger.
-I said, “grave danger?” You said--
-I recall--
I can have the reporter read--
I know what I said!
I don't have to have it read back--
Then why the two orders? Colonel?
Sometimes men take matters
into their own hands.
No, sir. You made it clear
your men never do.
Your men follow orders or people die.
So Santiago wasn't in danger, right?
You snotty little bastard.
-Your Honor, I ask for a recess.
-I'd like an answer.
The court will wait for an answer.
If Lt. Kendrick gave an order that
Santiago wasn't to be touched...
...why did he have to be transferred?
Colonel?
Kendrick ordered a Code Red
because that's what you told him to do!
Object!
And when it went bad, you signed a
phony transfer and doctored the logs!
You coerced the doctor!
Colonel Jessep,
did you order the Code Red?
-You don't have to answer that.
-I'll answer the question.
-You want answers?
-I think I'm entitled!
-I want the truth!
You can't handle the truth!
Son, we live in a world that has walls,
and those walls have to be guarded.
Who's gonna do it? You?
You, Lieutenant Weinberg?
I have a greater responsibility
than you can possible fathom.
You weep for Santiago
and you curse the Marines.
You have that luxury.
The luxury of not knowing what I know:
That Santiago's death, while tragic,
probably saved lives.
And my existence, while grotesque and
incomprehensible to you, saves lives!
You don't want the truth
because deep down...
...in places you don't talk about
at parties...
...you want me on that wall.
You need me on that wall.
We use words like honor,
code, loyalty.
We use them as the backbone
of a life spent defending something.
You use them as a punchline!
I have neither the time nor inclination
to explain myself...
...to a man who rises and sleeps under
the blanket of the freedom I provide...
...then questions the manner
in which I provide it!
I would rather you just said “thank you”
and went on your way.
Otherwise, I suggest you pick up
a weapon and stand a post.
Either way, I don't give a damn
what you think you are entitled to!
-Did you order the Code Red?
-I did the job--
-You're goddamn right I did!
I suggest the members be dismissed...
...so we can move
to an article 39A session.
-The witness has rights.
-Captain Ross?
Jack?
The members of the court will retire
until further instructed.
All rise.
What the hell is this?
Colonel, what's going on?
I did my job, I'd do it again.
-I'm going back to my base.
-You're not going anywhere.
-MP's, guard the colonel!
-Yes, sir.
-Captain Ross.
-What the hell is this?
Colonel Jessep,
you have the right to remain silent.
I'm being charged with a crime?
Is that what this is?
This is funny, that's what this is!
This is--
I'm gonna rip the eyes out of your head
and piss in your dead skull!
You fucked with the wrong Marine!
Colonel Jessep,
do you understand your rights?
You fucking people.
You have no idea
how to defend a nation.
All you did was weaken a country
today, Kaffee! That's all you did.
You put peoples' lives in danger.
Sweet dreams, son.
Don't call me son.
I'm a lawyer, and an officer
in the United States Navy.
And you're under arrest,
you son of a bitch.
The witness is excused.
All rise!
-Have you reached a verdict?
-We have, sir.
Lance Corporal Dawson,
Private First Class Downey.
On the charge of murder,
the members find the accused...
...not guilty.
On the charge of
conspiracy to commit murder...
...the members find the accused
not guilty.
On the charge of conduct
unbecoming a United States Marine...
...the members find the accused
guilty as charged.
The accused are sentenced
to time already served...
...and are ordered to be dishonorably
discharged from the Marine Corps.
This court-martial is adjourned.
All rise.
What did that mean?
Hal?
I don't understand. Colonel Jessep said
he ordered the Code Red.
-He ordered it. What did we do wrong?
-It's not that simple.
-We did nothing wrong!
-Yeah, we did.
We were supposed to fight for people
who couldn't fight for themselves.
We were supposed to fight for Willy.
Lieutenant Kaffee, I have to
take these men for some paperwork.
Harold?
Sir?
You don't need a patch on your arm
to have honor.
Ten-hut! There's an officer on deck.
O'Malley and Rodriguez,
what exactly could they testify to?
Probably that they had absolutely
no recollection of anything.
-Strong witnesses.
-And handsome too, didn't you think?
I'll see you around.
I gotta go arrest Kendrick.
Tell him I say hi.
Will do.
© anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous