My dad was a farmer.
Like everybody else back then.
Of course he didn't start that way.
The computer says you're too tight.
No, I got this!
-Crossing the Straits.
I've got to shut it down Cooper.
-Heyyy.
Shutting all down...
-Hey, we do not have to shut down  anything!
Dad?
Sorry Murph. Go back to bed babe.
I thought you were the ghost.
There's no such thing as a ghost babe.
-Grandpa says that you can get ghosts.
No, that's because
grandpa is too close to...
...being one himself. Go back to bed.
Were you dreaming about the crash?
Get your butt back in bed Murph.
The wheat had died.
The blight came and we had to burn it.
We still had corn.
We had acres of corn.
But mostly we had dust.
I guess I can't describe it.
It was just constant.
Just that, steady blow of dirt.
We wore little strips of sheet...
...sometimes over our nose and mouth.
So we wouldn't breathe so much of it.
Well when we set the table we always
set the plate upside down.
Glasses or cups, whatever it was, upside down.
Shake a leg. Murph, get your move on.
-One o'clock today, you and me...
...in the barn, Herbicide Resistance 101, check?
-Yessir.
Not at the table Murph!
Dad, can you fix this?
What the heck did you do to my lander?
-It wasn't me.
Let me guess. It was your ghost.
-It knocked it off my shelf.
It also knocks the books off.
-There's no such thing as ghosts dumbass.
Hey.
-I looked it up, it's called a poltergeist.
Dad, tell her.
-Well, that's not very scientific Murph.
You said that science was about admitting what we don't know.
-She's got you there.
Hey, start looking after all our stuff.
Coop.
Alright Murph, you wanna talk science?
Don't just tell me that you're afraid of some ghost.
No, you gotta go further.
You have to record the facts, analyze...
...get to the how and the why and present your conclusions.
Deal?
Deal.
-All right!
Have a good day at school.
-Hold up.
Parent-Teacher conferences,
parent, not grandparent.
Slow down turbo.
That's not a dust storm.
Nelson's torching his whole crop.
-Blight?
They're saying it's the last harvest for okra.
Ever.
He should have planted corn like the rest of us.
-Now you be nice to that Miss Hanley.
She's single.
-Well what's that supposed to mean?
Repopulating the Earth.
-Start pulling your weight young man.
Why don't you start minding
your own business? Old man!
All right Murph give me second.
Aha,....thirrrd.
Find a gear dumbass.
-Grind it! -Shut it Tom!
Whatcha do Murph?
-Ahh, she didn't do nothing.
Blew a tire is all.
-Murphy's Law.
-Shut up!
Grab the spare Tom.
-That is the spare.
Get the patch kit.
And how am I supposed to patch it out here?
You'll have to figure it out. I'm not always
gonna be here to help you.
What's goin' on Murph?
Why did you and mom name me after something that's bad?
-No we didn't?
Murphy's Law?
Murphy's Law doesn't mean that something bad...
...will happen.
What it means is whatever can happen...
And that sounded just fine with us.
Get in.
Get in, let's go.
What about the flat tire?
Yes.
It is an Indian Air Force drone.
Solar cells could power an entire farm.
Take the wheel Tom.
Go, go go!
Keep it pointed at that.
Faster Tom, we're losing it.
-Yes.
Point right at it.
Hang on, here we go, here we go.
Nice driving Tom.
Dad?
-Almost got it, don't stop, don't stop.
Dad?!
Tom!!!
Wha..? You told me to keep driving.
Well I guess that answers the ol'
'if I ask you to drive off a cliff' scenario.
We lost it.
-No we didn't!
Wanna give it a whirl?
Let's land it down there,
right at the edge of the reservoir.
Nicely done!
How long do you think it's been up there?
Delhi Mission Control went down
same as ours, 10 years ago.
So for 10 years?
Why'd it come down so low?
-I don't know.
Maybe the sun cooked it's brain
or it was looking for something.
-What?
Give me that large flatblade
Maybe some kind of signal.
I don't know.
What are you gonna do with it?
I'm gonna give it something socially
responsible to do...
...like driving a combine.
-Can't we just, let it go?
It wasn't hurting anybody.
Listen, this thing needs to learn how to adapt Murph,
like the rest of us.
So how's this work? Do you guys come with?
-I've got class.
This one, needs to wait.
What did you do?
-They'll tell you about it when you get in there.
Well am I gonna be mad?
-Not with me.
Just please, try not to.
Hey, relax....I got this.
You're late Coop.
-Yeah, we had a flat.
And I guess you had to stop off
at Asian fighter plane store.
No actually sir, that's a, that's
a surveillance drone.
With outstanding solar cells. It's Indian.
-Take a seat.
So, we got Tom's scores back.
He's gonna make an excellent farmer.
-Yeah he's got a knack for it.
What about college?
Well the university only takes a handful.
They don't really have the resources.
-I still pay my taxes.
Where does that money go? There's no more armies.
Well, they don't go to the university.
Look Coop, you have to be realistic.
You're ruling my son out for college now?
The kid's 15.
Tom's score simply isn't high enough.
-What's your waistline?
How about 32, about 33 inseam?
-I'm not sure I see where you're getting at.
You're telling me it takes two numbers
to measure your own ass...
...but only one to measure my son's future?
Come on, you're a well-educated man Coop...
...and a trained pilot.
-And an engineer.
Okay well right now, we don't need more engineers.
We didn't run out of television screens or planes;
we ran out of food!
The world needs farmers.
Good farmers like you, and Tom.
Uneducated farmers.
-We are a caretaker generation Coop.
And things are getting better.
Maybe your grandkids will get to be...
-Are we done here sir?
No.
Miss Hanley is here to talk about Murph.
Murph is a great kid, she's really bright.
But she's been having a little trouble lately.
She brought this in to show the other students.
The section on the lunar landings.
Yeah, it's one of my old textbooks.
She always loved the pictures.
It's an old federal textbook.
We've replaced them with the corrected versions.
Corrected?
-Explaining how the Apollo missions were faked to bankrupt...
...the Soviet Union.
You don't believe we went to the Moon?
I believe it was a brilliant piece of propaganda
that the Soviets bankrupted themselves...
...pouring resources into rockets and other useless machines.
Useless machines?
And if we don't want a repeat of the
excess and wastefulness of the 20th century...
...then we need to teach our kids about this planet.
Not tales of leaving it.
Y'know one of those useless machines they used to make
was called an MRI.
And if we had any of those left,
the doctors would've been able to find...
...the cyst in my wife's brain
before she died; instead of afterwards.
And then she would have been the one sitting here
listening to this instead of me...
...which would've been a good thing because
she was always the... the calmer one.
I'm sorry about your wife Mr. Cooper.
But Murph got into a fistfight with several of her classmates...
...over this Apollo nonsense.
So we thought it would be best to bring you in
and see what ideas you might have...
...for dealing with her behaviour on the home front.
Yeah, you know what,
there's a game tomorrow night.
She's going through a bit of a baseball phase,
her favorite team is playing.
There's gonna be candy and soda...
...I think I'll take her to that.
How'd it go?
-I got you suspended.
What??
-Cooper.
This is Cooper, go.
-Coop, those combines you rebuilt went haywire.
Just reset the controllers.
-I did that, but you should come take a look.
One by one they just teared off the fields
and headed over.
something's interfering with the compass.
Magnetism. Or somethin' such.
There's nothing special about which book.
I've been working on it, like you said.
I counted the spaces.
-Why?
In case the ghost is trying to communicate.
I'm trying Morse.
Morse?
-Yeah, dots and dashes. It's...
I know what Morse code is Murph.
But I still don't think your...
...bookshelf is trying to talk to you.
Had to reset every compass clock
and GPS to offset off the anomaly.
Which is?
-I don't know.
Now if the house had been built
on magnetic ore...
...we would have seen this the first
time we switched on the tractor.
I hear your meeting at the
school didn't go so well.
You heard?
It's like we've forgotten who we are, Donald.
Explorers, pioneers, not caretakers.
When I was a kid, it felt like
they made something new everyday.
Some gadget or idea.
Like every day was Christmas.
But 6, billion people,
Just try to imagine that.
And every last one of them
trying to have it all.
This world isn't so bad.
And Tom will do just fine.
You're the one who doesn't belong.
Born 40 years too late
or 40 years too early.
My daughter knew it. God bless her.
And your kids know it,
especially Murph.
Ahh we used to look up to the sky and wonder...
...at our place in the stars.
Now we just look down,
and worry about our place in the dirt.
Cooper, you were good at something,
and you never got a chance to do anything with it.
I'm sorry.
You didn't expect this dirt
that was giving you this food...
...to turn on you like that and destroy you.
In April I believe if I'm right,
15th of April I, I think.
This just happened at about 1:30 when that thing
came off the top of the canyon.
In my day we had real ball players. Who're these bums?
Well in my day, people were too busy...
...fighting over food to even play baseball.
Popcorn at a ball game is unnatural.
I want a hot dog.
School says you're gonna follow in my footsteps.
I think that's great.
You think that's great?
You hate farming dad.
Grandpa said.
Grandpa said huh?
Listen, all that matters is how you feel about it.
I like what you do.
I like our farm.
And you're gonna be great at it.
Let's get outta here.
All right it's a doozy.
Alright gang, lets mask up.
Tom, Murph? -Check.
-Check?
Murph, Tom, you guys shut your windows?
Murph.
The ghost.
-Grab your pillow.
You're sleeping with Tom.
It's not a ghost.
It's gravity.
I'm dropping Tom, then heading into town.
You wanna clean that up? When you've finished praying to it.
It's not Morse Murph, it's binary.
Thick is 1, thin is 0.
Coordinates.
That's it.
-I can't miss this.
Grandpa will be back in a couple of hours Murph.
But you don't know what you're gonna find.
And that, is why I can't take you.
Murph?
Grandpa will be home in a while, tell
him I'll call him on the radio.
Jesus!
What're you doing?
Oh d'you think it's funny? Huh?
You wouldn't be here if it wasn't for me.
Make yourself useful.
Hey Murph.
Murph.
I think this is the end of the road.
Didn't you bring the bolt cutters?
That's my girl.
Step away from the fence.
-Don't shoot, don't shoot. I'm unarmed.
My daughter is in the car.
Don't be afraid.
How did you find this place?
-Where is my daughter?
You had the coordinates for this facility marked on your map.
Where did you get those coordinates?
Where is my daughter?!
-Don't make me take you down again, sit down!
Oh d'you still think you're a Marine pal?
Marines don't exist. And you know what?
I've got grunts like you mowing my grass.
Where did you find those coordinates?
-Unless you wanna end up as my second lawnmower...
...no, I think I'll turn you into a valve of a vacuum or a dry cleaner.
No you won't.
TARS, back down please.
You're taking a risk using
ex-military security.
They are old and their control
units are unpredictable.
It's what the government could spare.
Who are you?
-Dr. Brand.
Yeah I knew a Dr. Brand once, he was a Professor.
-What makes you think I'm not?
Wasn't near as cute either.
Please Dr. Brand, I don't have
any idea what this is.
But I'm scared for my daughter,
and I want her by my side.
You give me that, and I'll tell you
anything you want to know.
Take the principal and the girl
to the conference room.
Your daughter is fine.
Bright kid.
Must have a very smart mother.
-It's pretty clear you don't want any visitors.
Why don't you let us back up from your fence
and we'll be on our way, huh?
It's not that simple.
-Well, sure it is.
Look I don't know anything about you.
I don't know anything about this place.
Yes you do.
Dad!
Hello Cooper.
Professor Brand.
Explain to me how you found this facility.
Kind of accidently stumbled upon it.
We were on a salvage run...
You're sitting in the best kept secret in the world.
Nobody stumbles in here, nobody stumbles out.
Cooper, please, cooperate with these people.
Well, it's kinda hard to explain.
We we.., we learnt these coordinates...
...from an anomaly.
-What sort of anomaly?
I hesitate to term it supernatural
but it damn well wasn't scientific...
You're gonna have to be specific
Mr. Cooper, right now.
-It was gravity.
Um what sort of gravitational
an- where was this thing?
Hey, I'm real happy that you're excited
about gravity bud, but...
...you're not getting any answers from us
until I get assurances.
-Assurances? -Yeah.
Like that we're getting out of here, and
I don't mean in the trunk of some car.
Don't you know who we are Coop?
-No Professor, I don't.
You know my father Professor Brand.
We're NASA.
NASA.
-NASA.
The same NASA, you flew for.
I heard they shut you down sir,
for refusing to drop bombs from...
...the stratosphere on the starving people.
When they realized that killing other people...
...was not a long term solution,
then they needed us back. In secret.
Why secret?
-Because public opinion wouldn't allow
spending on space exploration.
Not when you're struggling to put food on the table.
Blight. Wheat, seven years ago.
Okra, this year.
-Now, there's just corn.
And we're growing more than we ever had.
Yeah, but like the potatoes in Ireland
and the wheat in the dust bowl...
...the corn will die. Soon.
We'll find a way, Professor, we always have.
Driven by the unshakeable faith
that the Earth is ours?
Well not just ours, no.
But it is our home.
Earth's atmosphere is 80% nitrogen.
We don't even breathe nitrogen.
Blight does, and as it thrives,
our air gets less and less oxygen.
The last people to starve, will be the first to suffocate.
And your daughter's generation...
...will be the last to survive on Earth.
Murph is feeling a little tired, and was wondering
if she could take a nap in my office?
Yeah, thank you.
Okay.
Now you need to tell me, what your plan is to save the world?
We're not meant to save the world.
We're meant to leave it.
Rangers.
-The last components of our one versatile ship in orbit.
The Endurance.
Our final expedition.
You sent people out there looking for a new home?
The Lazarus missions.
-Sounds cheerful!
Lazarus came back from the dead.
-Sure, but he had to die in the first place.
There's not a planet in our
solar system that could sustain...
...life and the nearest
star is over a 1000 years away.
I mean, it doesn't even qualify as futile.
Where did you send them?
Cooper, I can't tell you any more
unless you agree to pilot this craft.
You're the best pilot we ever had.
-I barely left the stratosphere.
This team never left the simulator!
We need a pilot, and this is
the mission that you were trained for.
What, without even knowing?
An hour ago, you didn't even know I was alive,
and you were going anyway.
We had no choice.
But something sent you here.
They chose you.
-Who's 'They'?
How long, would I be gone?
-Hard to know.
Years.
-I've got kids Professor.
Get out there, and save them.
Who's 'They'?
-We started detecting gravitational anomalies,
almost 50 years ago.
Mostly small distortions to our
instruments in the upper atmosphere.
In fact I believe you encountered one yourself.
Yeah, in the Straits.
My crash, something tripped my fly-by-wire.
Exactly. But of all these anomalies,
the most significant is this.
Out near Saturn.
A disturbance of spacetime.
Is that a wormhole?
-It appeared 48 years ago.
And it leads, where?
-Another galaxy.
A wormhole is not a naturally occuring phenomenon.
Someone placed it there.
-'They'?
And whoever they are,
they appear to be looking out for us.
That wormhole let's us
travel to other stars.
It came right around when we needed it.
They've put potentially habitable
worlds right within our reach.
Twelve, in fact from our initial probes.
-You sent probes into that?
We sent people into it, 10 years ago.
The Lazarus missions.
12 possible worlds, 12 Ranger launches.
Carrying the bravest humans ever to live.
Led by the remarkable Dr. Mann.
Each person's landing pod
had enough life support for two years.
But they could use hibernation to stretch that...
...making observations on organics
over a decade or more.
Their mission was to assess their world and...
...if it showed potential, then they could send
out a signal and bed down for the long nap...
...wait to be rescued.
-And what if the world didn't show promise?
Hence the bravery.
You don't have the resources to visit all 12.
-No.
Data transmission back through the wormhole is rudimentary.
Simple binary pings on an annual basis...
...give us some clue as to which worlds have potential.
One system shows promise.
Well one, that's a bit of a long shot isn't it?
One system with 3 potential worlds?
Not a long shot.
Wait.
So if we find a home...
...then what?
-That's the long shot.
There is a plan A, and a plan B.
Did you notice anything
strange about the launch chamber?
This entire facility is a centrifuge.
Some kind of vehicle? A space station?
-Both. The plan A.
How do you get it off the ground?
The first gravitational
anomalies changed everything.
Suddenly we knew that harnessing gravity
was real.
So I started working on a theory and we started...
...building this station.
-But you haven't solved it yet.
That's why there's a plan B.
The problem is gravity.
How to get a viable amount of human life
off the planet?
This is one way. The plan B.
Population bomb.
Over 5000 fertilized eggs
weighing in at just under 900 kilos.
How would you raise 'em?
-With the equipment onboard we incubate the first ten.
After that, with surrogacy
the growth becomes exponential.
In 30 years, we could have
a colony of hundreds.
The real difficulty with colonization
is genetic diversity.
This will take care of that.
Yeah, but what about the people here?
You just, you'd give up on 'em?
My kids?
-That's why Plan A is a lot more fun.
How far have you got?
-Almost there.
You're asking me to hang everything...
...on an 'almost'.
-I'm asking you to trust me.
Find us a new home.
And by the time you return,
I would've solved the problem...
...of gravity.
I give you my word.
Go away!
Murph.
-Go. If you're leaving just go!
This world was never enough for you,
was it Cooper?
What, cause heading out there is what I feel like...
...I was born to do?
And it excites me?
Nah, it does not make it wrong.
-It might.
Don't trust the right thing
done for the wrong reason.
The 'why' of the thing, that's the foundation.
-And the foundation's solid.
We farmers, we sit here every year when...
...the rains fail, and we say:
Next year.
Well, next year ain't gonna save us, nor the one after that.
This world's a treasure Donald,
but it's been telling us to leave for a while now.
Mankind was born on Earth,
it was never meant to die here.
Tom will be alright,
but you got to make things right with Murph.
-I will.
Without making promises you don't know you can keep.
You have to talk to me Murph.
I need to fix this before I go.
Then I'll keep it broken so you'll have to stay.
After you kids came along, your mom, she
said something to me I never quite understood.
She said: Now, we're just here...
...to be the memories for our kids.
I think I now understand what she meant.
Once you're a parent, you're the
ghost of your children's future.
You said ghosts didn't exist.
That's right Murph.
Look at me.
I can't be your ghost right now.
I need to exist.
They chose me.
Murph, they chose me. You saw it.
You're the one who led me to 'em.
And that's exactly why you can't go!
I figured out the message.
One word. You know what it is?
Murph.
-STAY.
It says STAY dad.
-Murph.
You don't believe me!
Look at the books. Look it says STAY.
Why are you not listening? IT SAYS STAY!
-I'm coming back.
When??
One for you.
One for me.
When I'm up there in hypersleep,
or, or traveling at the speed of light,
or, near a black hole,
Time is gonna change for me.
And it's gonna run more slowly.
So, when we get back,
we're gonna compare.
-Time will run differently for us?
Yeah.
Maybe by the time I get back,
you and I, we might be the same age.
You and me.
What??
Imagine that!
Ah, Murph.
-You've no idea when you're coming back!!
No idea at all!
-Murph.
Murph, don't ma-, don't make me leave like this.
Murph!
Don't make me leave like this Murph!!
Hey,...I love you.
You hear me?
I love you forever.
And I'm coming back.
I'm coming back.
How did it go?
-Fine.
Just fine.
I love you Tom. -Travel safe, okay?
-Yeah. Take care of our place for me alright?
Huh?
-Uh huh.
Hey, can I use your truck while you're gone?
-You mean your truck?
I'll make sure they bring it back.
Look after my kids Donald.
Go for main engines. Start T minus 10.
Dad!
-9 -Dad!!
8, 7.
-DAD!!!
6, 5.
Main engines start.
4, 3, 2, 1. Booster ignition, and.
All engines look good.
Beginning roll program.
Prepare for stage one separation.
Stage one.
Everybody good? Plenty of
slaves for my robot colony?
They gave him a humor setting,
to fit in better with his unit.
He thinks it relaxes us.
-A giant sarcastic robot!
What a great idea!
-I have a cue light I could use when I'm joking, if you'd like?
That wouldn't be a problem, no.
Yeah you could use it to find your way back into the ship
after I blow you out the air lock.
What's your humor setting TARS?
100% -Let's bring it down to 75 please.
Stage two separation.
All feeds going manual.
-Going manual.
Deactivate probe heater 1, 2 and 3.
-Check.
Taking control.
-This is handover to you.
ABF check. Over.
Retro thrusters fuel cells 1, 2, 3.
100%
ex-mites.
It's hard leaving everything.
My kids.
Your father.
-We're gonna be spending a lot of time together,
-We should learn to talk.
-And when not to.
Just being honest.
-Well you don't need to be that honest.
Hey TARS, what's your honesty parameter?
-90%
90%?
Absolute honesty
isn't always the most diplomatic...
...nor the safest form of communication
with emotional beings.
-Okay!
90% it is Dr. Brand.
We're coming up on the Endurance.
12 minutes out.
Okay taking control.
Approaching module port, 500 meters.
It's all you Doyle.
Nice and easy Doyle, nice and easy.
Take us home.
Target locked.
Target locked. -Well done.
-Okay, helmets on.
Good job.
The door is not charging.
Never mind!
Cooper, you should have control.
-Control here.
Communication with ring module active.
That's initiate.
Are we ready to spin?
-Just a sec.
Hello CASE.
-Hello TARS.
Okay, we're all set.
-All right let's do it.
30% of spin.
One g.
How is gravity treating you back there?
Romilly, hey you okay?
-Yeah. -You all right?
Yeah, no I just need a minute.
Okay, I think we have some dramamine
in the hibe pad, I'm just gonna go get that.
It'll be in the cryo beds
Just be a sec. -Hey Brand?
Yeah? -Bring a lot.
Amelia, be safe.
Give my regards to Dr. Mann.
-I will Dad.
It looks good for your trajectory.
We've calculated, two years to Saturn.
That's a lot of Dramamine.
Look after my family will you please, sir?
We'll be waiting for you, when you get back.
A little older, a little wiser,
but happy to see you.
'Do not go gentle into that good night,'
'old age should burn and
rave at close of day,'
'Rage, rage against the dying of the light.'
'Though wise men at their end,
know dark is right.'
'Because their words had forked no lightning they'
'Do not go gentle, into that good night'
'Rage, rage against the dying of the light.'
Here, pills.
So alone.
-We have each other. Dr. Mann had it worse.
I mean them.
It's a perfect planet and we're
not gonna find another one like it.
No, it's not like, looking for a new condo.
The human race is going to be, adrift.
Desperate for a rock it can cling to
while it catches it's breath.
We need to find that rock,
and our 3 prospects are at
the edge of what might sustain human life.
Laura Miller's planet is the first.
Laura started our biology program.
Wolf Edmunds is here.
-Tell me about Edmunds.
Oh, um, Wolf's a particle physicist.
Any of them had any families?
No, no attachments. My father insisted.
They'all knew the possibility of...
...seeing another human being again.
I'm hoping we can surprise at least 3 of them.
Dr. Mann?
-Dr. Mann, well, he's remarkable.  He's the best of us.
He inspired 11 people to follow
him on the loneliest journey...
...in human history.
Scientists, explorers.
That's what I love.
Y'know out there, we would face great odds.
Death. But, not evil.
You don't think nature can be evil?
No. Formidable, frightening. But, no, not evil.
Is a lion evil because it rips a gazelle to shreds?
Just what we take with us then?
Yeah. This crew represents the best of humanity.
Even me, huh?
-Y'know what? We agreed, 90%.
Don't stay up.
I'll be in a minute.
Just remember Coop, you're literally wasting your breath.
Hey TARS, let's go over that trajectory one more time.
8 months to Mars.
Gravity powered slingshot around,
14 months to Saturn.
Nothing has changed on that.
Let me ask you something.
Dr. Brand and Edmunds.
-Why are you whispering? They can't hear you.
Dr. Brand and Edmunds, they close?
-I wouldn't know.
Is that '90% wouldn't know' or '10% wouldn't know'?
I also have a discretion setting Cooper.
But not a poker-face slick.
Hey guys.
Dad's about to go down for the long nap.
and I just, wanted to give you an update.
The Earth looks amazing from here.
You can't see any of the dust.
I really hope you guys are doin', doin' great.
I know you're gonna get this message,
Professor Brand assured me that he was gonna get it to you.
Alright, okay I love you!
Is it him?
-I don't think so Murph.
You must be Donald.
Hello Murph.
-Why are you in my dad's truck?
He wanted me to bring it for your brother.
He sent you a message.
She's pretty upset with him for leaving.
If you record any messages I can
get them transmitted to Cooper.
Murph is a bright spark.
Maybe, I should fan the flame.
She's already making fools of her teachers,
well, maybe she should come and make a fool out of you.
So where are they?
-Heading for Mars.
The next time you hear from Cooper,
they'll be coming up on Saturn.
They want me to repeat plant pathology.
It sucks. But, they said I could start
advanced agriculture a year early.
So...alright.
Well, I gotta go Dad.
Hope you're safe up there.
Sorry Coop, I asked Murph to say hi.
But she's as stubborn as her old man.
I'll try again next time.
Are you okay Rom?
This gets to me Cooper.
This, this.
Millimeters of aluminum protecting us
and then nothing...
...out there for millions of miles, won't kill us in seconds.
Did you know that some of
the finest solo yatchsmen in the world...
...don't know how to swim?
They don't know, and if they go overboard, it's done.
We are explorers Rom.
This is our boat.
Here.
This is the, relay probe?
-In orbit around the wormhole.
This is the wormhole and every
time we come around...
...we would receive images from
the other side of the foreign galaxy.
Like swinging a periscope around.
-Exactly.
So we got a pretty good idea,
what we're gonna find on the other side, huh?
Navigationally.
Hey guys, looks like we're gonna be
approaching the wormhole in about three hours.
Hey Coop, can we stop the spinning?
Why? -Because we are close enough to see it.
Aha.
Look, that's, that's it! That's the wormhole!
Say it, don't spray it Rom.
It's a sphere.
Well of course it is!
What you thought it would just be a hole?
No. It's just that all the illustrations I've ever seen they...
The illustrations, try to show how it works.
So they say you want to go from here, to there.
But this is too far.
So a wormhole bends space like this so you...
...can take a shortcut through a higher dimension.
Okay so, to show that they've turned 3-dimensional space...
...into 2 dimensions, which turns a wormhole in 2 dimensions...
...a circle.
What's a circle in 3 dimensions?
A sphere.
-Exactly. A spherical hole.
But who put it there?
Who do we have to thank?
I'm not thanking anybody
until we get outta here in one piece Rom.
Any trick to this Doyle?
No one knows.
The others made it, right?
At least some of 'em.
Everybody ready to say goodbye to our solar system?
To our galaxy.
Here we go.
Controls won't work here.
We are passing through the bulk.
Its space beyond our 3 dimensions.
All you can do is report and observe.
What is that?
I think it's 'Them'.
-Distorting spacetime?
Don't. Don't!
What was that?
First handshake.
We're...
We're here.
So the lost communications came through.
-How?
The relay on this side cached them.
It's years of basic data, no real surprises.
Miller's site has kept pinging 'thumbs up',
as has Dr. Mann's.
Edmunds went down three years ago.
-Transmitter failure?
Maybe.
He was sending the thumbs up right until it went dark.
But Miller's still looks good though, right?
Because she's coming up fast.
But there's one complication.
The planet is much closer to Gargantua
than we thought.
Gargantua?
-It's what we're calling the black hole.
Miller's and Dr. Mann's planets both orbit it.
And Miller's is on the horizon?
-Like a basketball around a hoop.
Landing there takes us dangerously close...
...and a black hole that big
has a huge gravitational pull.
Okay I-, I could swing around that neutron star...
-No no no, it's not that, it's time.
The gravity on that planet will...
...slow our clock compared to Earth's,.. drastically.
Well how bad?
Well, every hour we spend on that planet
will be, uhh, seven years back on Earth.
Jesus. -That's relativity folks.
Well, we can't just drop down there without...
-Cooper...
We have a mission.
-Yeah Doyle, we have a mission.
And our mission, Plan A is to find a planet...
...that can habitate the people
that are living on the Earth right now.
You can't just think about your family,
now you have to think bigger than that, alright?
I'm thinking about my family
and millions of other families.
Okay, Plan A does not work, if the people
on Earth are dead by the time we pull it off.
No, it doesn't.
That's why there's a Plan B.
Okay. Cooper's right.
We have to think about time as a resource just like...
...oxygen and food.
Going down there is gonna cost us.
Okay look, Dr. Mann's data is promising, alright,
but it's gonna take us months to get there,
and Edmunds, it's even further.
Now Miller hasn't said much.
But what she has said is very promising.
It's water, it's organics.
-You don't find that everyday.
No, you don't and just think about
the resources including time...
...that would be spent trying to get back here.
Romilly.
-Yeah.
How far off of Miller's planet
do we have to be to stay out of the time shift?
Alright, just back from the cusp.
-Which is here, just outside of Miller's planet.
Alright. Okay.
Here's Gargantua, here's Miller's planet.
Instead of taking the Endurance
into orbit around Miller's planet, which would...
...conserve fuel, but we'd lose a lot of time,
what if, what if we take a wider orbit around Gargantua,
parallel with Miller's planet,
outside of it's time shift, to here.
Then we take the Ranger down,
we get Miller, we get her samples,
we come back, we analyze, we debrief...
...we're in, we're out, we lose a little fuel.
But we save a lot of time.
That'll work.
-That's good. -There's not gonna...
be time for monkey business or chit-chat down there,
so TARS, you should definitely stay here.
CASE, you're with me.
Anyone else can stay.
If we are talking about a couple of years,
I could use the time to research gravity,
observations from the wormhole,
that's gold to Professor Brand.
TARS, factor an orbit around Gargantua,
conserve fuel, minimize thrusting.
Make sure we stay in range
from Miller's planet. You got it?
I wouldn't leave you behind, Dr. Brand.
You ready CASE? -Yep.
-You don't say much do you?
TARS talks plenty for both of us.
-Detach.
Romilly, are you reading these forces?
-Unbelievable.
A literal heart of darkness.
If we could just see the collapsed star inside,
the singularity, we'd solve gravity.
We can't get anything from it?
-Nothing escapes that horizon,
not even light.
All the answers are there, just no way to see it.
There's Miller's planet.
Goodbye Ranger.
This is fast for atmospheric entry.
Shouldn't we use the thrusters to slow?
-No.
I'm gonna use the Ranger's aerodynamics to save some fuel.
Air-brake?
-We wanna get down fast don't we?
Actually we wanna get there in one piece.
-Hang on.
Brand, Doyle, get ready.
We should be using the air-brake.
-Hands up CASE.
The only time I ever went down is
when a machine was easing at the wrong time.
You're going to get us killed.
-Just like reckless driving.
We're too fast. -I got this.
Should I get ready to detach?
-No. I need to feel the air.
Here we go.
It's just water!
The stuff of life.
-1200 meters.
Do we have a fix on her beacon?
-That I have, can you maneuver?
I gonna need to shave some speed.
I'm gonna spiral down on top of it, everybody hang on!
700.
On my cue CASE, on my cue.
500 meters.
Now!
Very graceful.
No, but very efficient.
What're you waiting for?
Let's go.
Go, go, go, go.
7 years per hour here.
Let's make it count.
This way.
About 200 meters.
Gravity's punishing.
-Been floating through space too long?
130% Earth's gravity.
Come on, come on, come on.
There's nothing here.
-should be right here.
If the, if the signal's coming from here, then...
Her beacon.
Wreckage.
-Where's the rest?
Towards the mountains.
Those aren't mountains.
They're waves.
-What?
Shit.
That one's moving away from us.
We need the recorder.
Brand, Doyle, back to the Ranger now!
I'm not, leaving, without, her data.
Get back here now. We do not have time.
The second wave is coming!
We are in the middle of a swell!
Get your ass back to the Ranger now!
Brand get back here now!!
Cooper, go, Cooper go, I can't make it. Go!
CASE, go get her.
GO!
-Get up, get up Brand.
Go go, go.
I'm not gonna make it!
-Yes you are. Yes you are!
Come on CASE has her, CASE has her! Get back here Doyle!
Dr. Brand.
To the hatch.
Go, go. Go.
Manually overriding inside hatch!
Cooper don't!
Cooper!
Engines are flooded!
I'll have to shut it down!
Oh shit!!
Whoaa!
CASE what's wrong?
-Chute's waterlogged, let it drain.
Goddamn it!!
I told you to leave me.
-And I told you to get your ass back here!
The difference is that one of
us was thinkin' about the mission.
-You were thinking about getting home!!
I was trying to do the right thing!
-Can you tell that to Doyle?
CASE, how much time?
-45 to an hour.
The stuff of life huh?
What's this gonna cost us Brand?
-A lot.
Decades.
What happened to Miller?
-Judging by...
...the wreckage she was
broken up by a wave soon after impact.
How's the hell the wreckage stayed together
after all these years, huh?
Because of the time slippage.
On this planet's time she,
she's landed hours ago, she...
...she probably just died minutes ago.
The data Doyle received was just the initial
status echoing endlessly.
Oh we are not prepared for this.
You eggheads have the survival skills
of a boy-scout troop.
Well we got this far on our brains,
farther than any human in history.
Well not far enough.
And now we're stuck here till there won't be anyone...
...left on Earth to save.
I'm counting every minute same as you Cooper.
Is there any possibility?
I dunno, maybe some way, I don't know...
...maybe if we could jump in a black hole
and gain back the years?
Don't shake your head at me!
Time is relative, okay.
It can stretch and it can squeeze, but,
it can't run backwards!
Just can't!
The only thing that can move across dimensions,
like time, is gravity.
Okay.
The beings that led us here,
they communicate through gravity, right?
Could they be talking to us from the future?
-Maybe.
Okay, if they can..?
They...
...are beings of 5 dimensions!
Right, to them, time might be
yet another physical dimension.
To them, the past might be a canyon
they can climb into,
and the future, a mountain that they can climb up,
but to us, it's not! Okay!
Look Cooper, I screwed up.
I'm sorry.
But you knew about relativity.
Brand.
My daughter is 10 years old.
Couldn't teach her Einstein's theories before I left,
Couldn't you have told your daughter
that you were going to save the world?
-No.
When you become a parent,
one thing becomes really clear,
And that's you wanna make sure your children feel safe,
and it rules out telling a 10 year old,
that the world's endin'.
Cooper.
How long for the engines CASE?
-A minute or two.
Well we don't have it!
Helmets on!!
Brand, co-pilot you're up.
CASE, run the cabin oxygen through the main thrusters.
We're gonna spark it!
-Roger that.
Depressurizing.
Engines up!
Hello Rom!
-I've waited years.
How many, how many years?
By now it must be,
23 years, 4 months, 8 days.
Doyle?
I thought I was prepared...I knew the theory...
...reality is different.
And Miller?
There's nothing here for us.
Why didn't you sleep?
-Oh I had a couple of stretches.
I stopped believing that you were coming back.
Something seemed wrong about dreaming my life away.
I learned what I could from the black hole
but I couldn't send anything to your father.
We've been receiving but nothing gets out.
-Is he alive?
Oh, yeah.
-Yeah? -Yeah.
We've got years of messages stored.
-Cooper.
Messages span 23 years.
Play from the beginning.
Hey Dad,
Just checkin' in, sayin' hi.
Umm, finished 2nd in school,
Miss Carlin's still giving me Cs though,
pulled me down,
but second's not bad.
Grandpa attended the ceremony.
Umm, oh, I met another girl dad.
I uh, I really think this is the one.
Her name is Lois.
That's her right there.
Murphy stole grandpa's car,
She crashed it, she's okay though.
Hey Dad.
Look at this!
You're a grandpa!
His name's Jesse.
I wanted to go with Coop, but
Lois says maybe next time.
And Donald says he's already got the 'great' part so,
we're not to call him that.
Say goodbye to Grandpa.
Goodbye grandpa.
Sorry, it's been a while.
It's..., what with Jesse and all...
Uhh, grandpa died last week.
We buried him out in the back 40 next to mom...
...and Jesse.
Which is where we would've buried you,
if you would've ever,... come back.
Murph was there at the funeral.
We don't see her that much, but she came for that.
You're not listening to this, I know.
All these messages are just, ... drifting...
out there in the darkness.
Lois says that, uh... I have to let you go.
And uh...
...so...
I guess... I'll let you go.
I don't know where you're dad.
But I hope that you're at peace. And...
Goodbye.
Hey Dad.
Hey Murph.
-You son of a bitch!
I never made one of these when you were still responding,
because I was so mad at you for leaving.
And then when you went quiet,
it felt like I should've lived with that decision,
and I have,
but today is my birthday,
And it's a special one,
because you told me,
you once told me that when you come back...
...we might be the same age.
And today I'm the age
you were when you left.
So it would be a real good time for you to come back!
I didn't mean to intrude,
It's just that I've never seen you in here before.
-Because I've never been in here before.
I talk to Amelia, all the time.
It helps.
I'm glad you've started.
-I haven't.
Just had something which needed to get out.
-I know they're still out there.
I know.
There are so many reasons why our communications
might not be getting through.
I know Professor.
I'm not sure, what I'm more afraid of.
Them never coming back or...
...coming back to find we've failed.
Then let's succeed.
-So,
back to the fourth iteration.
Let's run it through some new fields.
With respect Professor, we've tried that
hundreds of times.
-It only has to work once, Murph.
Every rivet that they strike could've been a bullet.
We've done well, in the world here,
whether or not we crack the equation,
before I kick the bucket.
Don't be morbid Professor.
-I'm not afraid of death.
I am an old physicist.
I'm afraid of time.
Time.
You're afraid of time.
For years we've been trying
to solve the equation without changing...
...the underlying assumption about time.
-And?
What it means, is each iteration
is an attempt to prove it's own proof,
it's recursive,...it's nonsensical.
Are you calling my life's work nonsense, Murph?
No, I'm saying that you've been trying
to finish it with one arm...
...no, with both arms tied behind your back.
And I don't understand why.
I am an old man Murph.
Can we take this point up at another time?
I want to talk to my daughter.
Stepping out into the universe,
we must confront the reality of interstellar travel.
We must reach far beyond our own lifespans.
We must think, not as individuals,
but as a species.
'Do not go gentle into that good night.'
TARS kept the Endurance right where we needed her...
...but the trip took years longer than what we anticipated.
We no longer have the fuel to visit both our prospects,
so, we've got to choose.
But how?
They're both promising.
And Edmunds data is better,
but Dr. Mann is the one who's still transmitting. So...
We've got no reason to suspect Edmunds data would've soured.
His world has key elements to sustain human life.
-As does Dr. Mann's.
Cooper, this is my field.
And I really believe Edmund's is the better prospect.
-Why?
Gargantua, that's why.
Look at Miller's planet.
Hydrocarbons, organics, yes;
But no life. Sterile.
We'll find the same thing on Mann's.
-Because of the black hole?
-Murphy's Law.
Whatever can happen, will happen.
Accidents are the first building block of evolution,
but when you're orbiting a black hole,
not enough can happen,
it sucks in asteroids, comets,
other events which would otherwise reach you.
We need to go further afield.
You once said that Dr. Mann, was the best of us.
He is remarkable.
we're only here because of him.
And, and yet here he is,
he is on the ground,
and he's sending a very unambiguous message,
telling us to come to his planet.
-Granted.
But Edmund's data is more promising.
-We should vote.
-Well, if we're going to vote, there's something you should know,
Brand, he has a right to know.
That has nothing to do with it.
-What does?
She's in love with Wolf Edmunds.
-Is that true?
Yes.
And that makes me want to follow my heart.
Maybe we've spent too long trying
to figure all this out with theory,
-You're a scientist Brand.
-So listen to me,
When I say that love isn't
something we invented, it's...
...observable, powerful.
It has to mean something.
-Love has meaning, yes, social utility...
...social bonding, child rearing,
-We love people who have died,
where's the social utility in that?
-None.
-Maybe it means something more,
something we can't...
...yet understand.
Maybe it's, some evidence, some...
...artifact of a higher dimension...
that we can't consciously perceive,
I'm drawn across the universe to someone...
...I haven't seen in a decade.
Who, I know, is probably dead.
Love is the one thing we're capable...
...of perceiving that transcends
dimensions of time and space.
Maybe we should trust that,
even if we can't understand it yet.
Alright Cooper,
Yes!
The tiniest possibility of
seeing Wolf again excites me.
But that doesn't mean I'm wrong.
-Honestly Amelia,
it might.
TARS, chart a course for Dr. Mann's.
We'll lose about a third again. Next year.
Next year, I'm gonna work Nelson's farm and I'm gonna make it up.
What happened to Nelson?
Murph, can I get you anything?
Would you like some more Souffl?
-No, I'm full. Thanks.
It was delicious.
Hand me that donut please.
Will you spend the night?
Your room is exactly as you left it. It's...
-I need to get back.
-My sewing machine is in there, but there's plenty...
-I need to...
...too many memories.
-Well, we have something for that.
Dust.
Lois, I have a friend who could...
...look at his lungs.
Amelia, I'm sorry.
-You're just being objective.
Unless you're punishing me,
for screwing up on Miller's planet,
-No, this wasn't a personal decision.
Well, if you're wrong, you have
a very personal decision to make.
Your fuel calculations
are based on a return journey.
Strike out on Mann's planet and you'll
have to decide whether...
...to return home, or push onto Edmunds with plan B.
Starting a colony could save us from extinction.
You might have to decide between
seeing your children again...
...or the future of the human race.
I trust you'll be as objective then.
He has been asking for you since he came to.
We were trying to reach you.
Murph?
-Hey.
I'm here Professor.
I think I let all down.
No, you got us this far.
We're close.
I will finish what you started.
Good, good Murph.
You had faith.
All those, all those years,
I asked you to have faith,
I wanted you to believe, that your father,... would come back.
I do Professor.
Forgive me Murph.
-There's nothing to forgive.
I lied Murph,
I lied to you.
There was no need for him, to come back.
There's no way to help us.
But the Plan A? All this?
All these people.
And the equation?
Did my father know?
Did he leave me?
'Do....not....go....gentle....'
No. NO!
You can't leave.
NO!!
Dr. Brand, I'm sorry to tell you
that your father died today.
He didn't feel any pain. He was at peace.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
Brand did you know?
He told you right?
You knew?
This was all a sham.
You left us here.
To suffocate.
To starve.
Frozen cloud.
It's okay.
Pray you never learn,
just how good it can be to see another face.
I hadn't had a lot of hope to begin with.
After so long I had none.
My supplies were completely exhausted.
The last time I went to sleep,
I didn't even set up a waking date.
You've literally raised me from the dead.
Lazarus.
What about the others?
-I'm afraid you're it sir.
So far, surely.
No. In our present situation...
...there's very little chance of rescuing any others.
Dr. Mann.
Dr. Mann, tell us about your world.
Our world, we hope...
Our world is cold, stark,
but undeniably beautiful.
The days are 67 hours long, cold.
The nights are 67 far colder hours.
The gravity is a very, very pleasant
80% of the Earth's.
Now here, where I landed,
the water is alkali.
And the air has too much ammonia in it
to breathe for more than just a few minutes.
But, down at the surface, and there is, a surface,
the chlorine dissipates,
the ammonia gives way to crystalline hydrocarbons.
Breathable air, to organics.
Possibly even, to life.
We might be sharing this world.
These readings are from the surface?
Over the years, I've dropped various probes.
-How far have you explored?
I have managed several major expeditions,
but with oxygen in...
...limited supply, KIPP there,
really did most of the legwork.
-What went wrong with him sir?
Degeneration. He misidentified the first organics...
...we found as ammonia crystals.
We struggled on for a time, but...
...ultimately I decommissioned him,
used his power source to keep the mission going.
I thought I was alone before I even shut him down.
-Would you like me to take a look at him?
No, no, needs a human touch.
Dr. Brand, CASE is relaying a message...
...for you, from the spaceship.
-Okay, be right there. Excuse me.
Dr. Brand, I'm sorry to tell you
that your father died today.
He had no pain. He was at peace.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Is that Murph?
-She's,...she's grown!
Brand did you know?
He told you right?
You knew?
This was all a sham.
You left us here.
To suffocate.
To starve.
Did my father know too?
Dad!
I just want to know, if you left me here to die?
I just have to know!
Cooper, my father dedicated
his whole life to plan A, I have...
...no idea what she's talking about.
I do.
He, he never even hoped to get the
people off the Earth?
No.
But he has been trying to solve
the gravity equation for 40 years.
Amelia, your father solved his
equation before I even left.
Then why wouldn't he use it?
The equation couldn't reconcile
relativity with quantum mechanics
You need more.
More? More what?
-More data. You need to see into a black hole.
The laws of nature prohibit a naked singularity.
-Romilly, is that true?
If the black hole is an oyster, then
the singularity is the pearl inside.
The gravity is so strong that it is always hidden...
...in darkness, beyond the horizon.
That's why we call it a 'black' hole.
Okay,...what if we see beyond the horizon?
We can't Cooper.
-There are some things that aren't meant to be known.
Your father had to find another way to save
the human race from extinction.
Plan B, a colony.
-But why not tell people?
Why keep it from us?
Because he knew how hard it would be
to get people...
...to work together to save the species
instead of themselves. Or their children.
Bullshit!
You never would have come here unless
you believed you were gonna save them.
Evolution has yet to
transcend that simple barrier.
We can care deeply, selflessly
about those we know.
But that empathy rarely extends beyond our line of sight.
-But the lie?
That monstrous lie?
-Unforgivable.
And he knew that.
He was prepared to destroy his own humanity,
in order to save the species,
he made an incredible sacrifice.
NO! No, an incredible sacrifice is being made,
by the people on Earth who're gonna die!
Because in his fucking arrogance,
he declared their case hopeless.
I'm sorry Cooper,
their case is hopeless.
No. No.
-We are the future.
Cooper.
Cooper, what I can do?
Let me go home.
You're absolutely positive?
His solution was correct. He's had it for years.
-It's worthless?
It's half the answer.
Okay, how do you find the other half?
Out there, in a black hole.
But stuck down on Earth?
Yeah?
I'm not sure you can.
God, they just pack up and leave.
What're they hoping to find?
-Survival.
Damn it!
Murph, don't, don't people have the right to know?
Panic won't help.
We just have to keep working, same as ever.
Yes, but isn't that exactly what
Professor Brand was manipulating...
-Brand gave up on us.
I'm still trying to solve this.
So, do you have an idea?
A feeling.
I told you about my ghost.
My dad thought I called it a ghost
because I was scared of it.
But I was never scared of it.
I called it a ghost because
it felt....like a person,
that was trying to tell me something.
If there is an answer
here on Earth, it's back there,
somehow in that room.
So I have to find it.
We're running out of time.
What about auxiliary oxygen scrubbers?
They can stay CASE.
I'll be sleeping most of the way anyway.
-Hey Coop. -Yeah?
I had a suggestion for your return journey.
-What is that?
Have one last crack at the black hole.
I'm going home Rom.
-Yeah I know.
This isn't gonna cost you any time.
It's a chance for the people on Earth.
Talk to me.
-Gargantua is an older spinning black hole.
It is what we call a 'gentle' singularity.
-Gentle?
They're hardly gentle.
But the tidal gravity is so quick that something...
...crossing the horizon fast, might survive.
A probe say.
What happens after it crosses?
After, the horizon,
is a complete mystery.
So, what's to say that there isn't some
way that the probe can...
...glimpse the singularity
and relay the quantum data?
If he's equipped to transmit every form of energy that can pulse...
Just when did this probe become a 'he' professor?
-TARS is the obvious candidate.
I've already told him what to look for.
I'll need the old optical transmitter on KIPP, Cooper.
-You would do this for us?
Before you get all teary,
try to remember that as a robot...
...I have to do anything you say.
-Your cue light's blinking.
I'm not joking!
I'm gonna need TARS to remove and adapt
some components from KIPP.
Well, I don't wanna disturb his archival functions.
-I'll supervise.
Alright.
-Dr. Mann, we need to find 3 secure sites.
One for Brand's lab and 2 for habitat.
Once those modules have landed,
you don't wanna move.
Well I can take you to the probes sites,
but I don't think this...
...these conditions are gonna hold.
I think we should wait.
CASE is headed back down with the
rest of the distillery equipment.
I would really like to secure those sites by nightfall.
Well, these squalls do usually blow over.
Okay then.
-You're gonna have to take a long-range transmitter.
Right.
-Are you charged? -Yeah.
Follow me.
TARS, 72 hours yeah? -Roger that Cooper.
Brand told me why you feel you've got to go back.
But I'd be remiss
if didn't at least mention that a mission...
...such as ours could certainly do
with an extra engineer.
Oh you better slow down turbo.
Safety first CASE, do not forget.
-Safety first Cooper.
I have to tell you Dr. Mann
I'm honored to be a part of this.
But once we set up
base camp and...
...secure those modules, my work is done here.
I'm going home.
We have attachments.
But even without a family,
I can, promise you that, that yearning...
...to be with other people is remarkable.
That emotion is, at the foundation, of what makes us human.
How long have you had that cough?
-For a while.
Mom let's me play in here.
I don't touch your stuff.
Just take this gently.
You know why we couldn't just send
machines on these missions, don't you Cooper?
A machine doesn't improvise well,
because you can't programme the fear of death.
Our survival instinct is
our single greatest source of inspiration.
Take you for example,
A father, with a survival instinct
that extends to your kids.
What does research tell us, is the
last thing you're gonna see, before you die?
Your children.
Their faces.
At the moment of death, your mind
is going to push you a little bit harder, to survive.
For them.
Hey, I bet you're Coop.
Why don't you have a seat here for me.
It's bad.
They cannot stay here.
OK? -Yes.
TARS, what's taking so long?
-Professor, I'm having trouble completing the boot-up.
I don't understand?
It's funny.
When I left Earth,
I thought I was prepared to die.
The truth is, I never really, considered...
...the possibility that my planet wasn't the one.
Nothing turns out the way it's supposed to be.
-Let's go.
Aaaaaaaaaaaah!!
What is this?
-What are you doing??
I'm sorry, I can't let you leave
with that ship.
We're going to need it
to complete the mission.
Once the others, realize what this place isn't.
We cannot survive here.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
They can't stay here anymore.
You have to leave, right now.
Hey buddy, let me make something abundantly clear...
You have a responsibility.
-Shit.
Coop, get her stuff, she's goin' home.
-Dad didn't raise you to be this dumb Tom!
Dad didn't raise me, grandpa did,
and he's buried...
...out back with mom and Jesse.
All the data?
No. I tried to do my duty Cooper.
But I knew, the day that I arrived here,
this place had nothing...
...and I resisted the temptation, for years
But, I knew that, if I just pressed
that button, then, somebody would come and save me.
You fucking coward!
-Yes.
Yes.
Listen, if you're not gonna go, let your family go.
Just let,...save your family.
And go to live underground? With you?
Pray that daddy comes to save us?
Dad's not coming back. He never was coming back.
It's upto me!
Are you going to save everybody?
Because dad couldn't do it?. -DAD DIDN'T EVEN TRY!!
Dad just abandoned us!!
He left us here to die.
-Nobody is going with you.
You're gonna wait for your next kid to die?
Get out, and don't come back!
Do what you want with those things.
Stop it!
No. NO!
Dr. Mann there's a 50-50 chance that you're gonna kill yourselves.
Those are the best odds I've had in years!
Don't judge me Cooper.
You were never tested like I was.
Few men have been.
You tried your best Murph.
Do you feel it?
The survival instinct.
That's what drove me.
It's what drives all of us, and it's what's gonna save us.
Because I want to save all of us.
For you Cooper.
I'm sorry, I can't,
I can't watch you go through this. I'm sorry.
I thought I could, but I can't.
I'm here, I'm here for you.
Just listen to my voice Cooper, I'm right here.
You're not alone.
Do you see your children?
It's okay.
They are right there with you.
Did Professor Brand tell you that poem
before you left?
Do you remember?
'Do not go gentle,
into that good night'
'Old age should burn, and rave
at close of day.'
'Rage, rage against the
dying of the light.'
Help! Help!
-Cooper?
CASE!
-Brand.
No air!
Cooper. Cooper I'm coming.
CASE! -I have a fix.
Go, go, go!!
Cooper we're coming, hang in there, don't talk!
Breathe as little as possible. We're almost there!
There is a security lockout sir, it requires...
...a person to access the functions.
It's all yours sir.
Cooper!!
Come on!
I see him! I see him!
To the right. Bank right!
Cooper!
Cooper, I'm here.
Take this!
Joey bring the tankers!
This data makes no sense.
I'm sorry.
-What?
Mann, was lying!
Romilly!
Romilly, do you read me?
Romilly!!
STEP BACK PROFESSOR!! STEP BACK!!
Romilly. -Romilly! Do you read me?!!
Keep watch!
Lois!
-What happened to caution CASE?
Safety first Cooper.
Romilly, Romilly do you read me? This is Brand.
Romilly!
-Dr. Brand, Cooper, there's been an explosion.
Dr. Mann's compound.
TARS, TARS! 10 o'clock.
Tell me when TARS is aboard.
Romilly did not survive.
I could not save him.
-TARS is in. -I'll take it from here!
D'you have a fix on the Ranger?
-He is pushing into orbit.
Ah, if he takes control
of that ship we're dead.
He'd maroon us?
-He is marooning us!
Get downstairs. Go wait by the car.
Come on.
Get in the back!
Get in the back seat, now!!
Dr. Mann please respond!
Dr. Mann please respond!!
He doesn't know the Endurance's docking procedure.
-But the autopilot does.
Not since TARS disabled it!
-Nice!
What is your trust setting TARS?
-Lower than yours apparently!
Do not attempt docking, I repeat do not attempt docking.
Auto docking sequence withheld.
Override. -Unauthorized.
-Override!
Unauthorized.
Do not attempt docking, I repeat Do Not! attempt docking! Please resp...
Moving slowly towards the Endurance.
Imperfect contact.
-Override! -Hatch locked.
Has he locked on yet? -Imperfectly.
Dr. Mann...
Hatch lockout disengaged.
Dr. Mann, do not, I repeat, do not open the hatch.
I repeat, do not open the hatch.
If you open the hatch, the airlock will depressurize.
What happens if he blows the airlock?
-Nothing good.
Okay, pull back, pull back. Retro thrusters full
move back CASE! -Maximum. -Back!
CASE relay my message
to the onboard computer...
...and have it rebroadcast
as emergency PA.
Dr. Mann, do not open the air hatch.
I repeat, do not... -Brand?
I don't know what he said to you?
But I'm taking command of the Endurance.
And then we're gonna talk about completing the mission.
Dr. Mann, listen to me!
This is not about my life, or Cooper's life,
This is about all mankind.
There is a moment...
It is not...
Oh, my God.
Cooper there's no point in using your fuel...
-Analyze the Endurance's spin.
-Cooper, what are you doing?
-Docking.
Computer says rotation at 67, 68 rpm.
Get ready to match our spin with the retro thrusters.
-It's not possible.
-No, it's necessary.
The Endurance is entering the atmosphere.
It does not have a heat shield.
CASE, you ready?
-Ready.
Cooper, this is no time for caution.
CASE, if I pass out, you take the stick.
TARS, get ready to engage
the docking mechanism.
The Endurance is starting to heat.
-20 feet out.
I need three degrees starboard Cooper.
-10 feet out.
Cooper, we are, lined up!
Initiate spin!
Hold on TARS!
HOLD ON!
We're locked Cooper. -EASING UP!
Slowly.
Retro thrusters!
Main engines on!
We're getting out of orbit. Come on baby!
Shutting engines.
Okay we're out of orbit!
Okay! And for our next trick!
It better be good.
We're headed into Gargantua's pull.
Shit. CASE take the stick.
-Roger that.
Cooper, we're slipping towards Gargantua.
Shall I use the engines?
No, we gotta let her slide as far as we can!
Give it to me.
-It's good news and bad news Cooper.
Yeah, to hell with it TARS!
Just give it to me straight.
The back-up generator kicked in,
so the system's stable. They're all good.
Good! Okay.
The navigational hub's been completely destroyed.
We don't have enough life support to make it back to Earth,
but I think we can scratch over to Edmund's planet.
-What about fuel?
It's not enough.
But I have a plan.
We let, Gargantua, pull us down close...
to the horizon, and a powered slingshot...
...around launching us towards Edmund's planet.
-Manually?
That's what I'm here for.
I'll take us just inside the critical orbit.
What about the time slippage?
Neither one of us have time
to worry about relativity right now Dr. Brand.
Sorry Cooper.
Once we have gathered enough speed...
...around Gargantua,
we use Lander 1,
and Ranger 2 as rocket boosters...
...to push us out of the black hole's gravity
The Lander's linkages have been destroyed,
so we're going to have
to control it manually.
Once Lander 1 is spent,
TARS will detach...
...and get sucked right into that black hole!
-Why does TARS have to detach?
We have to shed the weight, escape gravity.
-Newton's third law.
The only way humans have figured out of getting somewhere
is to leave something behind.
Cooper, you can't ask TARS to do this for us.
-He's a robot...
...so you don't have to ask him to do anything.
-Cooper, you asshole!
Sorry, you broke up a little bit there.
-It's what we intended Dr. Brand.
It's our only chance to save people on Earth,
if I can find a way to transmit the quantum data I'll find in there,
maybe they'll make it.
Let's just hope there is still someone there to save.
Maximum velocity achieved.
Prepare to fire speed thrusters.
Ready?
-Ready. -Ready.
Main engine ignition in 3, 2, 1...
Engines of Lander 1 on my command,
3, 2, 1...
Engines of Ranger 2 on my command,
This little maneuver is gonna cost us 51 years!!
You're not too bad for someone pushing 120!
Lander 1, prepare to detach on my mark,
3, 2, 1...
Detach!
Goodbye TARS!
-Goodbye Dr. Brand. See you on the other side Coop.
See you there slick!
Okay CASE. Nice reckless flying!
Learned from the master!
Ranger 2, prepare for detachment.
-What, no, no! Cooper, Cooper,
what are you doing??
Newton's third law.
You gotta leave something behind!
You said we had enough resources for both of us!
-We agreed Amelia,
90%
No!
Detach.
Okay, we're nosing down.
Approaching the event horizon.
Portside, dipping down beneath it..., to go through it.
Heading towards... blackness...
It's all black!
TARS, do you read me? It's all black.
TARS, do you read me? Over.
We're...we're getting screens,
We're getting interference.
Losing control of the stick.
We've got flashes.
Flashes of lightness and blackness.
There's a turbulence in the gravity.
Computers going down.
The gravitational pull, we're losing control of the stick.
Murph! Murph, come on!
Murph!
Murph! Murph!! Murphhh!!
Murph!!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Murphhhhhhhhh!!!!!
Murphhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh!!!!!!!
No, no!!!!!!!
If you're leaving just go!
-No.
No, don't go. Don't go you idiot!
Don't go!!!
Morse, Morse, Morse.
'S'
'T'
'A'
'-'
Murph, we don't have time for this, come on!
STAY!!!
Come on, come on, Murph, Murph, come on!
What's it say? What's it say? What's it say?
It say's STAY!
Tell him Murph. Make him stay.
Make him, make him stay Murph.
STAY
Make him stay Murph!
Don't let me leave Murph!!!
Don't, DON'T LET ME LEAVE MURPH!!!
NO, NO, NO, NOOO!!!.
It was you!!
You were my ghost!!
Cooper, Cooper come in.
-TARS??
Roger that.
You survived?
-Somewhere...
...in their fifth dimension.
They saved us!
Yeah? Well who the hell is 'They'?
And just why would they want to help us?
I don't know, but they constructed
this three-dimensional space...
...inside their five dimensional
reality to allow you to understand it.
-Yeah well it ain't working.
Yes it is. You've seen that time,
is represented as a physical dimension.
You've worked out that you can exert a force
across spacetime.
-Gravity...
...to send a message?
-Affirmative.
Gravity...
...can cross the dimensions, including time?
-Apparently.
Do you have the quantum data?
-Roger, I have it.
I've translated it on all wavelengths...
...but nothing is getting out Cooper.
-I can do this, I can.
But such complicated data to a child?
-Not just any child.
Come on dad!
Murph, the fire's out! Come on!
Even though you communicate it here,
she won't understand it's significance for years!
No, no, I get that TARS, but
we've got to figure something out alright...
...or the people on Earth are gonna die!
Think, think, think!
Cooper, they didn't bring
us here to change the past.
Say that again.
-They didn't bring us here, to change the past.
No, they didn't bring us here at all.
We brought ourselves!
TARS, give me the coordinates for NASA, in binary.
In binary, roger, translating data.
It's not a ghost.
It's gravity.
-Don't you get it yet TARS?
I brought myself here!
We're here to communicate,
with the three dimensional world!
We are the bridge!
I thought they chose me.
But they didn't choose me, they chose her!
-For what Cooper?
To save the world!
All of this! In one, little girl's bedroom.
Every moment, it's infinitely complex.
They have access to infinite time and space...
...but they're not bound by anything!
They can't find, a specific place in time.
They can't communicate.
That's why I'm here.
-I'm here to find a way...
...to tell Murph,
just like I found this moment.
-How Cooper?
Love TARS, love!
It's just like Brand said,
my connection with Murph, it is quantifiable.
It is the key. -Why are we here?
To find out how to tell.
The watch!
Encode the data in the
movement of the second hand.
TARS, translate the data into Morse
and give it to me.
Translating the data to Morse.
Cooper, what if she never came back for it?
She will. She will.
He's coming Murph!
Okay, coming down!
-How do you know?
Because I gave it to her!
Roger Morse is dot dot dash dot,
Dot, dot, dash, dot,
dot, dash, dot, dot,
It was him!!
All the time!!
I knew it!!!
Dad saved us!!
Eureka!!!
It's traditional.
Did it work?
-I think it might have.
How do you know?
Because, the bulk beings
are closing the Tesseract.
Don't you get it yet TARS?
They're not beings.
They're us!
What I've been doing for Murph,
they've been doing for me!
For all of us.
-Cooper, people couldn't build this.
No, no. Not yet. But one day.
Not you and me. But people.
A civilization that's evolved
past the 4 dimensions that we know.
What happens now?
Mr. Cooper.
Let's take it slow sir.
Nice and easy Mr. Cooper.
Remember you're no spring chicken anymore.
Actually you are one hundred and twenty four years old.
Take it slow sir.
You were, um, extremely lucky.
The Rangers found you with only minutes
left in your oxygen supply.
Where am I?
Cooper station.
Currently orbiting Saturn.
Cooper station?
What nice of you to name it after me!
What?
-Well, the station isn't named after you sir,
It's uh, it's named after your daughter.
Although she's always maintained
just how important you were.
-Is she still alive?
She'll be here in a couple of weeks.
She is far too old to be
transferred from another station...
...but when she heard that you'd been found.
Well this is, this is
Murphy Cooper we're talking about!
Yes it is!
We'll have you checked out of here
in a couple of days.
I'm sure you'll be excited to see what's in store.
I actually uhh, did a paper on you,
in high school,
I know all about your life back on Earth.
Oh yeah, right.
Sir, if you could follow me?
You've got a really good situation.
So um, when I made my suggestion to Ms. Cooper,
I was delighted to hear that she thought it was perfect.
Well of course, I didn't speak to her in person.
My dad was a farmer.
Like everybody else back then.
Anyway, there just wasn't enough food.
We had strips of sheet to
cover our nose and mouth.
So we wouldn't breathe so much of it.
She did confirm, just how much you loved farming.
She did? Did she?
Well, home sweet home!
Everything is in its place and
faithfully reproduced.
Yes.
Hey, is this? -Oh yeah, the machine
we found out near Saturn with you.
It's power source is shot,
but we can get another one if you want.
Yes, please!
Settings.
General settings.
Security settings.
Honesty, new setting.
95%
Confirmed. Additional customization?
Humor: 75%
Confirmed.
Auto self destruct T minus 10, 9...
Let's make that 60%.
60% confirmed.
Knock Knock. -You want 55?
Is this really what it was like?
It was never this clean slick.
I don't care much for this, pretending
we are back where we started.
I want to know where we are?
Where are we going?
Mr Cooper. -Yes?
-The family is all in there.
Family?
Yeah, they all came out to see her.
She's been in cryo sleep for almost 2 years.
You told them I liked farming?
It was me Murph!
I was your ghost!
I know.
People didn't believe me,
they thought I was doing it all myself. But...
...I knew who it was.
Nobody believed me.
But I knew you'd come back.
How?
Because my dad promised me!
I'm here now Murph.
I'm here!
No. No parent should have
to watch their own child die.
I have my kids here for me now.
You go!
Where?
Brand.
She's, out there.
Setting up camp.
Alone, in a strange galaxy.
Maybe right now she's, settling in...
...for the long nap.
By the light of our new sun.
In our new home.